<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/resources/xslt/page.xsl"?>
<my:doc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2000/10/XMLSchema-instance"
	xmlns:my="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/xml/webpage/1"
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
	title="Game Night"
	style="default"
	revision="$Revision: 1.12 $">

<my:infobox title="Would you like to play a game of chess?">
<p>
Okay, so chess is a fun game, but it's not exactly the most exciting of games.
And I'm sure that most people are so sick of "party" games like Taboo and
Cranium that they wish they'd never played them.  Well never fear, we ensure
you that this once in a period-of-time event will be 100% Taboo and Cranium
free.
</p>
<p>
Here's the deal.  We've got lots of interesting, geeky, and fun games that we
don't get play enough.  The solution, invite a bunch of fun and interesting
folks over to play our games.  So come on over and experience something new.
</p>
</my:infobox>
<my:infobox title="The Lowdown">
<p>
Patrick and Kristina's Game Night<br />
Friday, March 11th, 2005<br />
Starting around 6ish (If you'd like to come earlier, we can do a dinner thing too)<br />
436 44th St <a href="/misc/housemap.html">directions</a>, <a href="http://tinyurl.com/5rzyx">map</a><br />
412-606-9730 (Patrick)<br />
</p>
<p>
If you've got an interesting game you'd like to bring, let us know and I'll
add it to the list, as long as it isn't Cranium or Taboo.  Seriously, no
Cranium or Taboo.  I'm not joking about this.
</p>
<p>
We'll provide some munchies, but like all events like this, if you'd like to
bring something along to munch on, you're more than welcome.
</p>
</my:infobox>
<my:infobox title="Possible Games">
<ul>
<li>Chez Geek</li>
<li>Munchkin</li>
<li>Illuminati</li>
<li>Settlers of Catan</li>
<li>Monopoly</li>
<li>Clue</li>
<li>Interesting games you may bring</li>
</ul>
</my:infobox>
<my:infobox title="Who's Coming">
<p>
I'll update this section as I find out who is coming.
</p>
<ul>
<li>Patrick Wagstrom</li>
<li>Kristina Wagstrom</li>
</ul>
</my:infobox>
<my:infobox title="In the future">
<p>
We'll probably have these a bit more often after we move.  Consider this the
last great blowout at our currrent place in Lawrenceville.  We're moving in
April to Greenfield and we'll probably have more game nights after we move.
</p>
</my:infobox>

<my:links>
	<my:link name="home" url="/"/>
	<my:link name="projects" url="/projects/"/>
	<my:link name="resume" url="/resume/"/>
	<my:link name="photos" url="/photos/"/>
	<my:link name="weblog" url="/weblog/"/>
	<my:link name="wedding" url="/wedding/"/>
	<my:link name="tutorials" url="/tutorials/"/>
	<my:link name="research" url="/research/"/>
</my:links>
</my:doc>
