<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: pimpbot | My Delusional Dream]]></title>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/blog/categories/pimpbot/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-12T20:51:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Wagstrom]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not Work Safe URL Plugin]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/12/04/nwsurls/"/>
    <updated>2003-12-04T22:51:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/12/04/nwsurls</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the same vein as the lasturls plugin, I created a nws/nsfw plugin.  Now this
one monitors the stream of urls entered in the channel and records them.  If
someone types "nws" or "nsfw" on a single line by itself, the url is added
to the list of URL that are not safe.  In this way you can return home and
easily get just the pr0n urls (or stuff that other's might find questionable)
without having to filter everything else.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tinyurl and LastURLs for PimpBot]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/12/03/tinyurlandlasturls/"/>
    <updated>2003-12-03T09:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/12/03/tinyurlandlasturls</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote a couple of new plugins for PimpBot last night.  The first is a module
that will take any URL that is posted in the channel over a certain length
and submit it to <a href="http://tinyurl.com/">TinyURL</a> to get a tiny
version of the URL.  The result usually comes shortly after a message as
the bot has got to submit the request to TinyURL.  I should add some timeout
functionality to it in case TinyURL goes down so the bot doesn't miss stuff.</p>

<p>The second collects all the URLs posted in the channel and allows you to query
them.  Normally this is done by typing !urls, at
which point the most recent 10 urls will be returned.  You can also specify a
search string, like !urls sportsbybrooks which will
return the 10 most recent urls that contain a specific string in them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to PimpBot]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/12/02/pimpbotintro/"/>
    <updated>2003-12-02T23:10:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/12/02/pimpbotintro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Reject was recently updated and as a result of the upgrade some software
that was installed on there no longer works, among them the antiquated
TCL-SQL module that powered the explain module of B|shop (the ircbot of #zoes).
Being as I don't have access to fix it myself, I just decided to write
my own bot.  So here comes PimpBot.</p>

<p>PimpBot is a simple Python script that works with Twisted to provide a
plugin based framework for the creation of an IRC bot.  Everything works
as plugins that are written in Python and loaded at runtime.  Currently
there is a database access module and an explain module.  I'm working
on a userlist module.  After that I'll work on some more channel protection
stuff.  I'll post the code as I get further along, right now I've got
finals and stuff to worry about though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
