<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rfidPrivacy | My Delusional Dream]]></title>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/blog/categories/rfidprivacy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-12T20:51:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Wagstrom]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RFID Privacy Workshop - Session 1 (Prelim)]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/11/19/session1/"/>
    <updated>2003-11-19T22:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/11/19/session1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First up in session was Ravi Pappu from <a href="http://www.thingmagic.com/">ThingMagic</a> talking about security and
privacy in the EPC network.  The first that needs to be made is that the EPC
network is going to be some SCARY SHIT.  I don't mean to swear, but if
Christian fundamentalists thought the UPC was the mark of the beast then EPC is
the antichrist.  Essentially everything is linked through this global network
to track down EXACTLY what product a particular EPC code relates to.  A very
good point is that the benefits of this system have yet to be clearly
articulated.  There isn't a reason of yet of why consumers should like this
stuff.  After that he went into various threats to privacy resulting from RFID.
The most interesting of which were the constellation effect where all your RFID
tags create a shadow around you making you easy to track.  Also is the
possibility that transactions amongst individuals would be trackable.  I'd
imagine this would be the RIAA/MPAA's dream as they could track the second hand
market and shut it down.</p>

<p>Then came what was the coolest piece of technology at the show, the blocker tag
from <a href="http://www.ari-juels.com/">Ari Juels</a> of <a href="http://www.rsasecurity.com/">RSA Security</a>.  Due to the way that RFID
is structured there can obviously be contention amongst devices when a reader
is present.  Basically what the blocker does is stop playing nice and always
say yes.  In this respect it says it is both a rutabega, a 12 pack of gilette
razors and a roll of toilet paper at the same.  This makes it impossible to use
readers when you're around one of these.  However, this isn't playing nice and
we need to respect some standards (otherwise I'd already own a cell phone
blocker and turn it on during meetings).   Thus there is the proposal to create
a privacy space in RFID.  So when you purchase a device a bit is flipped to
move the device from the normal space to the privacy space where the blocker
will block requesting it.  However, the blocker is still theoretical and has
not yet been built, leading to two problems.  First, it might not work in which
case there is need to find a new solution.  The second is that it might work in
which case it would be outlawed by the government.  Fortunately for us there is
a solution, line a bag with tinfoil and that should keep those nasty signals
out and away from the stuff in the bag.  Now the RFID chip embedded inyour
sandal is another story.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RFID Privacy Workshop - Morning (Prelim)]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/11/19/morning/"/>
    <updated>2003-11-19T22:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/11/19/morning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This blog entry is a work in progress.  Please give me feedback.</p>

<p>November 15th, 2003 marked the first <a href="http://www.rfidprivacy.org/">RFID
Privacy workshop</a>.  It was held at the <a href="http://www.mit.edu/">MIT
Media Lab</a> and organized by Simson Garfinkel (Ph.D. student and author of
Database Nation).  Initial impressions were that it was larger than we
expected, and it appears larger than the organizers expected too.  The room for
the very important events of breakfast and lunch could hardly contain the
people.  This was the first indication that it is a hotter topic than most
people, including the organizers, thought.</p>

<p>There were two morning keynotes, from two opposite ends of the spectrum.  Mario
Rivas, executive vice president of Philips Semiconductors, gave the first talk
about some of the business aspect of RFID.  Most of this information wasn't new
to anyone who has followed RFID.  Namely the facts that RFID can greatly
improve the efficiency of supply chains and would be a boon to any retail store
that has to occasionally do inventory.  What was a little disturbing is how he
glossed over security quite a bit.  The comment was made that they have the
best cryptologists working for them and are able to stay two steps ahead of the
bad guys, but for many in the audience with a knowledge of cryptology, this did
not calm our nerves.  I'd much rather know how the data is encrypted between
the reader and tag than to just know it is encrypted.  A final good point that
was made was the deployment of RFID devices.  Many organizations have RFID
cards that are used for entry, MIT does and so did <a href="http://www.iit.edu/">IIT</a> when I went there (both under the brand name
of "Prox" cards).  Also, many transportation agencies are deploying RFID
passes, such as the London Transport and the Chicago Transit Authority.  These
are nice for the consumer because the cards don't expire and value can be
replaced if lost.  They're nice for the provider because they can track
wherever you get on a train or bus.</p>

<p>Next up was Katherine Albrecht from <a href="http://www.spychips.com/">CASPIAN</a>, a consumer rights organization
that seeks more assurances about the safety and privacy of RFID devices.  A
great amount of points were discussed about how manufacturers are relying on
the complete apathy of consumers to push this technology through.  Some of the
largest threats are problems arising from hidden tags and the possibility of
data aggregation.  She also spent some time showing off some of the tags and
showing how various companies like <a href="http://www.walmart.com/">Wal-Mart</a> have been using them in tests
without telling people (this is yet another reason why you should boycott
Wal-Mart, that and they only sell crap).</p>

<p>Matt Reynolds from <a href="http://www.thingmagic.com/">ThingMagic</a> was the
next person up to talk, this was probably one of the most helpful talks and
made me happy that I spent time getting my electrical engineering degree even
though I'll probably never use it.  For complete details, please check out his
<a href="http://www.rfidprivacy.org/papers/physicsofrfid.pdf">slides</a>.
Basically the issue is this, with a 1W transmitter you will not be able to
read any RFID chip from more than 20 meters away, the laws of physics just don't
allow it as you'll get too much noise over such a distance.  This is because
for 915MHz tags (the most common) the power decreases with square of distance.
For 13.56MHz it decreases with the distance to the sixth power.  Furthermore,
because we're still sending radio waves they should be fairly easy to block by
things like metal or big bags of water salt water (humans).  Thus ramming an
RFID tag in your armpit will effectively kill it.  I'll stress again, read the
slides, they'll make you feel better about how RFID is not this solution
to/cause of all the worlds woes that one might think it is.</p>

<p>The initial session concluded with a panel discussion by the first three
presenters.  There wasn't anything really new that was brought up at this
point, just some clarifications and a nice slide form Katherine that showed
the distances that various manufacturers claimed their tags could be read
from.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back from Boston]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/11/19/rfidprivacyreturn/"/>
    <updated>2003-11-19T21:38:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/11/19/rfidprivacyreturn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got back from Boston around 6pm tonight.  Took a nap and then caught up on what <a href="http://www.mythtv.org/">MythTV</a> got in my absence.  For some reason the encoder doesn't seem to be encoding at the proper bit rate anymore.  It means I loose half the space, which is a lot when you've got a small hard disk.</p>

<p>Anyway, the conference was great.  I learned a lot of interesting stuff and met some cool people.  I've got lots of notes that I'm going to be going through this week once I get caught up in my classes again.  I'll post em to my blog in incremental sections.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RFID Privacy Conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/11/14/rfidprivacy/"/>
    <updated>2003-11-14T22:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2003/11/14/rfidprivacy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm in Boston for the next few days at the <a href="http://rfidprivacy.org/">RFID Privacy Conference</a>.  I've never been to
Boston before, this should be a bit of an adventure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
