<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: politics | My Delusional Dream]]></title>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/blog/categories/politics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-12T20:51:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Wagstrom]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I am not a climatologist, and neither are most of these people]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2012/01/28/i-am-not-a-climatologist-and-neither-are-most-of-these-people/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-28T19:16:47-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2012/01/28/i-am-not-a-climatologist-and-neither-are-most-of-these-people</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the past couple of days I have twice received an <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970204301404577171531838421366.html?mod=WSJ_hp_mostpop_read">opinion piece from the Wall Street Journal which suggests that the models used for estimating climate change are grossly pessimistic and that we really need not be concerned with anthropogenic climate change</a>. It was signed by sixteen scientists and engineers. The problem is that almost none of these people are climatologists - which is the field they are claiming is producing invalid science. Anyone can call themselves a scientist - having a Ph.D. helps - but, just because you are a scientist does not mean that you can speak authoritatively on all issues related to science. Stephen Hawking is a brilliant scientist, but he studies astrophysics, not climatology. I trust him on a lot of things, but I wouldn't trust him on climate change. Nor would I trust Albert Einstein, Louis Pastuer, Marie Curie, or Isaac Newton on issues of climate change.</p>

<p>So, who are these climate change deniers that have the right frothing at the mouth again? Let's take a quick look.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Claude_All%C3%A8gre">Claude Allegre</a>, former director of the Institute for the Study of the Earth, University of Paris</strong> - Is a geochemist, which might make him qualified. It's hard to tell as he has spent most of his time doing political work recently. He appears to have a strong contrarian streak, such as in 1996 when he insisted that asbestos was harmless and that anger over it was caused by mass hysteria. That last time I checked the link between asbestos and mesothelioma was pretty firm.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J._Scott_Armstrong">J. Scott Armstrong</a>, cofounder of the Journal of Forecasting and the International Journal of Forecasting</strong> - This one gave me a decent chuckle. At first I thought he was a climate forecasting scientist, nope. Armstrong's expertise is in marketing style forecasting, as in trends. His journal is also published by Elsevier. I think I threw up a little in my mouth.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.rockefeller.edu/research/faculty/labheads/JanBreslow/">Jan Breslow</a>, head of the Laboratory of Biochemical Genetics and Metabolism, Rockefeller University</strong> - A medical doctor and not a climatologist. Breslow is perhaps most well known for his work on heart disease. This is great work he has done, but it's not atmospheric science.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.marshall.org/experts.php?id=252">Roger Cohen</a>, fellow, American Physical Society</strong> - It's difficult to find information on Cohen. Prior to retirement he worked for ExxonMobil research, but that's about all I can find. I can't seem to find any publications on any issue. However, he does have a very common name, making him hard to google. He frequently consort with William Happer, who appears later in the list.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_E._David_Jr.">Edward David</a>, member, National Academy of Engineering and National Academy of Sciences</strong> - As a member of the National Academy of Engineering I have great respect for Dr. David. However, he is an electrical engineer and has been largely retired from research for more than 20 years. Did I mention he was director of research at Exxon from 1977-1985?</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Happer">William Happer</a>, professor of physics, Princeton</strong> - Seems to have moved away from research as he's advanced in his career. During his prime he was a leader in the field of spectroscopy. Which, in case you didn't know, has nothing to do with climate change. During his 2009 testimony to congress he indicated that an increase in CO2 is good for the planet because it's good for plants. Yes, very much like the Competitive Enterprise Institute's "CO2, We Call it Life" vieo.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.sp.phy.cam.ac.uk/SPWeb/home/mjk1.html">Michael Kelly</a>, professor of technology, University of Cambridge, U.K.</strong> - Kelly primarily works on semi-conductors, specifically SRAM. He is not a climatologist or even a chemical engineer or chemist.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.sourcewatch.org/index.php?title=William_Kininmonth">William Kininmonth</a>, former head of climate research at the Australian Bureau of Meteorology</strong> - Kininmonth is, perhaps, a meteorologist, although there is little information easily available about his activities. It is known that he is not a prominent researcher in any field and his "Australasian Climate Research Institute" is run out of his home and appears to be only his own writings.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Lindzen">Richard Lindzen</a>, professor of atmospheric sciences, MIT</strong> - Lindzen is perhaps the most qualified individual on this list. He is well known for his skepticism of anthropogenic climate change. He stands out from the other signatories because he can speak with true scientific authority on the issue.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.mii.vt.edu/MACR/faculty/mcgrath.html">James McGrath</a>, professor of chemistry, Virginia Technical University</strong> - McGrath studies polymers and fuel cells. He is a scientist, but not a climate scientist.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.fas.org/about/bio/nichols.html">Rodney Nichols</a>, former president and CEO of the New York Academy of Sciences</strong> - This one took me a while longer to find out information about. I believe that Dr. Nichols is a physicist from Harvard, which means he could be a climatologist. However, looking at his publication record for the last 40 years you'll find that most of his work is dealing with science and technology policy -- issues that are close to my heart. However, this doesn't qualify him as a climatologist. I'm sure he is well learned in a variety of topics, but I don't believe he has a deep knowledge of the current research on climatology.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burt_Rutan">Burt Rutan</a>, aerospace engineer, designer of Voyager and SpaceShipOne</strong> - I have great respect for Burt Rutan and his creations. He has done a huge amount to make space accessible for all. However, he's an aerospace engineer, a field which studies the design of aircraft, not the atmosphere or climate science.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harrison_Schmitt">Harrison H. Schmitt</a>, Apollo 17 astronaut and former U.S. senator</strong> - As an astronaut Harrison Schmitt was on the mission that took the famous "<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Blue_Marble">Blue Marble</a>" picture of the earth. In fact, evidence indicates that Schmitt most likely took the photo that has been credited with being a critical catalyst for the environment movement in the 1970's. Outside of his astronaut career he was a university professor, geologist, and senator from New Mexico. None of these are related to the atmosphere or climate science.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nir_Shaviv">Nir Shaviv</a>, professor of astrophysics, Hebrew University, Jerusalem</strong> - Shaviv is primarily an astrophysicst known for his work on cosmic rays and luminosity. He has his own theory of global warming which says that the cosmic rays of the sun are responsible for global warming. His theory has not been widely accepted and has faced great challenges because of the fact that the solar output has been decreasing since the mid 1980's.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henk_Tennekes">Henk Tennekes</a>, former director, Royal Dutch Meteorological Service</strong> - Also a professor of Aeronautical Engineering at Penn State, Tennekes is most well known for his work on turbulence in airflows. In fact, he literally wrote the book on it. Unfortunately, that's not a book on climate change. He was reportedly ousted from the Royal Dutch Meteorologic Service for his denial of climate change and his sometimes reliance on biblical texts for justification. Look, I'm a Christian and a scientist, but I realize that I can't use biblical texts to justify my work, that's not how science works.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antonino_Zichichi">Antonio Zichichi</a>, president of the World Federation of Scientists, Geneva</strong> - Primarily a sub-nuclear physicist who has worked at labs like CERN and FermiLab. His title of President of the World Federation of Scientists is self bestowed as he is the founder. It should not be considered to be an analog to the Federation of American Scientists. He is a highly cited researcher, and has done significant work in popularizing science in Italy, but he is not a climatologist.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Out of the sixteen people listed I count one atmospheric scientist, Lindzen, and a half, Allegre. In any community of scientists you'll have dissenters. The fact that they could round up only one and a half climate scientists for this letter should show you just how strong the case for global warming really is. Want more evidence? 255 scientists, all members of the National Academy of Science, including 11 Nobel laureates wrote a scathing response, <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5979/689.full">rejected by the Wall Street Journal and later published in Science</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confusion Abounds!  DTV Transition Delayed Until June 12.  Or is it?]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/02/05/confusion-abounds-dtv-transition-delayed-until-june-12-or-is-it/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-05T11:27:20-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/02/05/confusion-abounds-dtv-transition-delayed-until-june-12-or-is-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/media/2009/02/dtvarmageddon.png"></p>

<p>The United States House of Representatives <a href="http://www.govtrack.us/congress/bill.xpd?bill=s111-352">voted 264-158 to extend the DTV Transition until June 12th</a>.  The vote went largely along party lines with a handful of each party switching sides, but it wasn't enough to be called a bi-partisan approval.  However, it fails me why this should be a partisan issue in the first place.  In approving the delay, the House left in the provision that allows TV stations to switch over before June 12th if they choose.  This is an appealing option to many stations because of the high cost of running two sets of transmitters.  At a price of $0.12KWh, a 100,000W transmitter costs $12/hour to run, $288/day, and $8640/month.  A station with a 100,000W transmitter could therfore be expected to spend about $34,560 to keep their transmitter powered until June 12th.  Clearly they have incentive to commit to transition early.</p>

<p>The primary reason why many folks voted for this bill was because of a chart that Nancy Pelosi circulated that showed the number of consumers on the waiting list for DTV converter boxes in each congressional district (you can find the chat on <a href="http://arstechnica.com/telecom/news/2009/02/dtv-delay-passes-264-158.ars">Ars Technica's coverage of the bill</a>).  Every single congressional district has between 1200 and 9200 people on the waiting list for coupons -- and a shocking 53,372 people in Puerto Rico.  Furthermore, every district saw their waiting list increase by at least 100 people, and some as many as 800 over the course of a weekend.  Ostensibly, approving a delay would ensure that these 181,013 new households and 1,781,218 previously registered households receive their coupons.</p>

<p>However, the program is out of money.  The only way that coupons are being sent out right now is if someone's coupon expires.  If the list were capped at the number of people on it currently, and that seems unlikely, then the government still needs to come up with $156,983,520 to pay for those coupons.  Unfortunately, in approving the delay, no provision was made for this funding.</p>

<p>Furthermore, there is no evidence that delaying the transition will actually help people.  Two areas have already transitioned to DTV, Wilmington, NC which transitioned as a test in September, 2008, and the entire state of Hawaii, which transitioned last month to not interfere with a species of bird that is active in February.  If we look at Hawaii, however, there still are 2,974 people on the waiting list, with 129 new people just last weekend.  These are people who failed to submit their coupon request until after the transition happened.  My guess is that there's a lot of grandmas out there who will be in the same boat -- in addition to folks who have cable for most of their televisions, but may want to ditch it because of budget concerns (talk about a great lockin for cable companies).</p>

<p>So, now we're left with an utter mess.  Instead of having a solid date for when analog broadcasting dies, stations can choose to switch anytime between Februrary 17 and June 12.  My hunch is that within a metro area, not all stations will switch at the same time, just confusing folks more -- "I only get the station with the fifth grader show.  Where's my CSI:Albany?"  Furthermore, it's looking more and more unlikely that the government will come through with the estimated $300-$500 million necessary to fund the coupon program -- they've got bigger things to worry about than whether or not people can continue to watch "How I met your Mother" and "Knight Rider".  Finally, President Obama has yet to sign the bill, but has indicated support for the bill.  Therefore all the official advertising, even on <a href="http://www.dtv2009.gov/">dtv2009.gov</a> still lists February 17th as the date.</p>

<p>Yes the transition has come at a really bad time.  We're fighting two wars.  Our economy is collapsing.  Now, the way they've handled transition indicates that it will be a mess for a long time to come.  In the end, the winners may be services like Dish network and Comcast, who are sending out millions of flyers around the country advertising budget rate plans starting at $9.99 for local channels.  The losers will almost certainly be the people who waited and haven't requested their coupons, and will be left without whatever crappy summer programs the networks unleash on us in June.  But hey, it's June, it should be nice outside.  I hear there's lots of things to do outside.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delay the DTV Transition Again?]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/02/02/delay-the-dtv-transition-again/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-02T13:33:40-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/02/02/delay-the-dtv-transition-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/media/2009/02/dtvbyebye.png"></p>

<p>For the last 12 months American's have been incessantly pounded with messages about the upcoming DTV transition.  In simple terminology, if you've got an old TV hooked up to rabbit ears, it's going to break in the very near future.  The history of this problem is long, and complex, but it generally amounts to the fact that HDTV provides better quality in a smaller swath of frequency.  Frequency that is very valuable and can get the government a couple of billion dollars at auction.  Last year <a href="http://gizmodo.com/370350/fcc-700mhz-auction-winners-verizon-wins-c-block">Verizon managed to snag a good chunk of the 700MHz spectrum</a> currently used for television for it's next generation 4G phone services.</p>

<p>In order to make this transition a little easier for Americans, the government approved the <a href="https://www.dtv2009.gov/">DTV coupon</a> program, which gives anyone who asks for it two $40 cards that can be used to the purchase of a digital to analog converter -- in essence these boxes downsample HD content so folks with SD televisions can still use them.  When I was visiting relatives over the holiday season I saw that some of them had these and they generally worked pretty well.  Unfortunately, the program has been such a success that they've now run out of money and folks who waited are being put on a waiting list until more money is made available for the program.  In essence, these folks will loose their over the air TV signals on February 17th.</p>

<p>Congress, of course, wants to ensure that everyone can continue to watch their Wheel of Fortune and Nightline, and don't want to be blamed by old people who vote, but turn off their hearing aids during advertisements and haven't paid attention to the transition, for breaking their televisions.  Two weeks ago the Senate voted to approve a delay until June.  The house attempted to bring up under special rules, which would require a 2/3rds vote.  Republicans got together and found enough people to vote against bringing it up on special rules, largely because the process would forbid them from proposing amendments, to make the vote fail.  The DTV transition was still February 17th.</p>

<p>Now, much more recently the Senate has again passed a bill to extend the DTV transition period until June, and <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2009/02/modified-dtv-delay-bill-set-for-house-revote-tuesday.ars">the House will vote on it tomorrow (Tuesday, February 3rd)</a>.  It's anyone's call about whether or not this bill will pass -- there's good chance it will as Democrats will most likely vote for it after shooting down Republican attempts to litter the bill with tax cuts.  President Obama will then sign the bill sometime later this week, less than two weeks before the transition, and magically, after we've been hearing for over a year that the transition would be February 17th, it will be moved to June.  Talk about confusion.</p>

<p>But wait, it gets even better than that.  Many stations have already put plans together and scheduled contractors to take down their analog transmitters.  If you're a small station this is a no-brainer because for the last several years you've been broadcasting on two different transmitters -- which can eat a large portion of your budget.  The new bill will do nothing to stop stations from shutting down their analog transmitters.  In others words, instead of having all channels going to static at once, we'll be left with a situation where there is piecemeal and unpredictable deactivation of the analog spectrum taking place anytime between February 17th and the new deadline in June.  I'm sure Grandma is going to love that.</p>

<p>So now, we're in the final countdown.  15 days to go, and it's unclear if everything we've been hearing is correct or not.  However, the bigger problem is that there has been information about this transition for more than a year now -- you even see <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Shutdownmessage.jpg">crawls running during television shows</a>.  Any television sold post 2007 must be able to accept ATSC digital television.  There still are people who don't know about this?  Plausible.  After all, there are people who believe all sorts of crazy things, like that Saddam was behind 9/11.  So you can't expect news to get to these people and inform them.  At what point will the government realize that some people will just have to be screwed by this transition?  My hunch is that there are few people left who have heard about the transition and haven't done anything about it.  Especially considering that most Americans get their television through pay services such as cable or satellite and won't be affected regardless.  I feel a little bad for the people who haven't gotten their coupons yet, and I hope this is remedied soon, but fortunately February and March are pretty boring times in the US -- few natural disasters, no elections, and only hockey and basketball are playing.  Maybe they should try sitting down with a book for bit instead?  Certainly that's got more to it than the 5 phrases they see nightly on Wheel of Fortune.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Administration, New Website, and Lost Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/01/20/new-administration-new-website-and-lost-content/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-20T20:35:57-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/01/20/new-administration-new-website-and-lost-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2009/01/400px-barack_obama_after_inaugural_address_1-20-09.jpg">
		<figcaption>I have just wiped away eight years of internets content! </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>One of the more interesting aspects of the inauguration today was how the website at <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/">whitehouse.gov</a> switched over from the Bush administration to the Obama site right around noon.  Shortly thereafter folks noticed <a href="http://www.kottke.org/09/01/the-countrys-new-robotstxt-file">the drastic contrast in robots.txt files</a> between the two administrations.  Some folks are saying this represents a difference in attitudes between the administrations, which may be true, but it's much more likely a result of a differences in information architecture and the smaller amount of content on Obama's whitehouse.gov.</p>

<p>However, this highlights something a bit more interesting, when the website was switched over massive amounts of content were immediately rendered obsolete and for most purposes lost.  I'd imagine that National Archives has a copy of them, just like they archive email from the executive branch, but that doesn't make it that easy to get access too.  While much of the information on the whitehouse.gov site is partisan banter, there are some elements that are lost -- like the <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20080307031231/http://www.whitehouse.gov/kids">Whitehouse Kids page</a> (archive.org link), and Hurricane Katrina pages (not archived).</p>

<p>Given the increased importance of information placed on the web and the importance of a smooth transition of power, shouldn't some work be done to archive this information?  I realize that it may not be possible to continue to provide interactive elements as the system administrators have left, but a static archive would be helpful and also serve as a valuable resource for folks looking back at previous presidencies.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Political Telemarketers or Scammers?]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2008/02/15/political-telemarketers-or-scammers/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-15T16:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2008/02/15/political-telemarketers-or-scammers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning while sitting in my office, I received a telephone call from a presidential campaign seeking a donation.  I found this interesting because I have yet to donate to any presidential candidate this year.  While I was more than happy to donate some money to the campaign, a thought came into my head while dealing with the guy on the phone -- how do I know you're really working for campaign X?  It would be trivial for someone to say they were with a campaign, start calling people, and get a few credit cards here and there.</p>

<p>My first inclination was to check the caller ID on the call, then enter the number into Google and see if it came back with anything. Unfortunately, the caller ID was blocked.  I thought about it and realized that someone with a moderate amount of skill and planning, of which it seems most scammers have neither, could get an account at <a href="http://www.spoofcard.com/">SpoofCard</a> and make their call seem as though it was indeed coming from the campaign.  Thus, I could not use this obvious piece of information as verification of the mans identity.</p>

<p>I realized that if they had my name and phone number they must have had other information on me too.  I asked the gentleman on the phone where my information was obtained from, and he informed me that it was from a list of donors to a previous round of presidential campaigns.
If that was the case, then they should have information such as my address on file also.  Sure enough, they had my old address from 2004  on file.  While this was enough to convince me that the man was most likely affiliated with a real political campaign it wasn't enough to convince me to donate money over the phone.  A nefarious individual could still look up information about past addresses and then figure out which one would have been valid at the time.  However, this is a lot of work for a relatively small probability of payoff.</p>

<p>I volunteered to donate money over the internet, and the man was very against the option, replying that is possible to process the transaction over the phone in under a minute -- that's funny, on a high speed connection I can find a candidate's web page and donate money in under a minute.  Anyway, after some going back and forth I informed the marketer that he had succeeded in reminding me that I had been planning to donate money (it was even in my copy of <a href="http://www.thinkingrock.com.au/">thinking rock</a>), but I couldn't do it online because it didn't feel secure.</p>

<p>So, for anyone who reads this, what actions can a campaign take to make sure that a recipients of marketing calls know they're legitimately calling from the campaign?  Absent of political beliefs, what credentials would a person over the phone have to communicate to you to get you to donate?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
