<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: c | My Delusional Dream]]></title>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/blog/categories/c/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-12T20:51:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Wagstrom]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Presenting slAntiIdle]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2006/11/17/slantiidle/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-17T00:17:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2006/11/17/slantiidle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here's a tasty little treat for you.  The <a href="http://secondlife.com/community/linux-alpha.php">Linux client</a> for <a href="http://www.secondlife.com/">Second Life</a> allows synthetic events to be sent to it.  What's this mean?  Basically, it means that you can script X input with other programs throught the wonders of XSendEvent. Where I find this comes in useful is in the places where you have to camp.  Specifically, if you're playing the horribly named casino game "Death Camp" you can make a killing just by occasionally sending keys to keep you from going idle and getting kicked of Second Life.  That's exactly what this does.</p>

<p>So here's what you need to do.  Open up subversion and check out <a href="https://secure.wagstrom.net/svn/projects/slAntiIdle">https://secure.wagstrom.net/svn/projects/slAntiIdle</a> then compile it and just run it.  Start it up after you've started Second Life and it should automatically find your running Second Life client and send a series of alternating up and down keys, once every 30 seconds.  I've found this is just enough to keep me from going idle.  Plus, if you're walking around, you usually won't notice the intrusion.  Anyway, now that you've got it loaded, go to a casino with Death Camp.  Camp on a chair, plop the money in, and let the client run in the background.  I find it's nice just to keep Second Life running in the background at school like this.  It's a good way to make some nice profit.  Especially if you're cheap like me and don't want to pay.  We'll so how long this lasts.</p>

<p>Oh yeah, and for <a href="http://kenneths.org/flog/">Kenny</a>, I told you I would start blogging once you went away for a while.  Hah.  Don't worry, I'll stop by the time you get back from South America.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[xmlsnipe now on SourceForge]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2004/10/18/xmlsnipefreshmeat/"/>
    <updated>2004-10-18T21:04:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2004/10/18/xmlsnipefreshmeat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I went and created a <a href="http://www.sourceforge.net/">sourceforge</a>
project page for <a href="http://xmlsnipe.sourceforge.net/">xmlsnipe</a>.
I also submitted a link to <a href="http://www.freshmeat.net/">freshmeat</a>
that hopefully will be posted soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[xmlsnipe]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2004/10/17/xmlsnipe/"/>
    <updated>2004-10-17T22:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2004/10/17/xmlsnipe</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been looking for a simple command line tool that allows some manipulation
of XML files.  Basically, what I need is a little program that allows me to
print out some nodes, delete others, replace some more, and in general, have
a good old time mangling XML files.  The main reason is because one of the tools
we use in our labs requires the use of a XML configuration file.  If I want
to run in a batch mode, I need a tool that lets me vary parameters easily and
rerun the program with the changed parameters.</p>

<p>Enter xmlsnipe!</p>

<p>xmlsnipe is a little program that I'm writing that is a little like a sed clone
for XML files.  You may ask, why shouldn't I just use SED, well, the answer is
because that just wouldn't be right.  Also, I needed to sharpen up my coding
skills.  That being said, while it would be easy to write xmlsnipe in something
that has support for XML, like Python, C#, or Java, I wanted to make it more
difficult to write, and more primal.  I'm writing it in C.</p>

<p>I've got it going okay so far.  It's already automakeized and what not.  I must
say that <a href="http://www.freedesktop.org/software/pkgconfig/">pkgconfig</a>
makes this much easier.  Anyway, right now it can just delete and print nodes.
I'm in the process of making it able to change values of nodes.  Which is what
I really needed it to do.  Once that happens I'll probably make a sourceforge
page for the project and put a small release up on my
<a href="/projects/">projects</a> page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
