<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: htpc | My Delusional Dream]]></title>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/blog/categories/htpc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-12T20:51:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Wagstrom]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raid 1 Performance on Windows 7]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2011/05/10/raid-1-performance-on-windows-7/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-10T19:44:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2011/05/10/raid-1-performance-on-windows-7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>About a year ago I ditched Ubuntu and MythTV on my media center box for Windows 7 Ultimate. To be honest one of the main reasons I did this was for NetFlix, but also because I got tired of having to tweak my media center all the time and Windows 7 Media Center just works. Also Windows 7 is smart enough to know how to sleep and wake up from sleep, saving my lots of money over the course of a year.</p>

<p>In order to ensure that I never lose any episodes of high quality television programs, I keep my boot and recorded television programs on a Raid 1 (mirror) set of 2 TB drives. Because all of the data is copied across two different drives in theory it have higher speed reads than a single drive, but lets take a look. I admit this isn't the most intelligent of tests, as it's simply done using ATTO Disk Benchmark. First, the results for an individual 2TB Samsung drive:</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2011/05/Independent_Overlapped_0.5_to_8192_1GB.png">
		<figcaption>Performance for a single 2TB drive </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Next, the performance for a pair of 2TB Samsung drives working in a RAID-1 mirror set:</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2011/05/Mirrored_Overlapped_0.5_to_8192_1GB.png">
		<figcaption>Performance for a mirrored pair of 2TB drives </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>As we see, there is very little difference between the two. In almost all cases the two setups are within about 10% of each other. There clearly is no intelligence in Windows 7 for spreading reads across multiple drives. One of the major side effects of setting up a RAID 1 is that when something goes wrong you'll need to rebuild your mirror. Unfortunately, this seems to happen much more often would be desirable and it often renders the machine nearly unusable. However, contrary to my suspicions, this has nothing to do with massively decreased disk performance:</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2011/05/Resynching_Overlapped_0.5_to_8192_1GB.png">
		<figcaption>Performance of mirrored 2TB drives while resynching </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>I have no idea what the spike in the middle is for. It's clear, however, that the reason for the system bogging down is not because of decreased drive performance but rather because of other issues. This might be CPU related as my media center box is running on a very old AMD Athlon64x2 4400+ on a motherboard that is almost six years old. So, the resynching problems might be because of CPU issues, or it could be because of something else (perhaps CrashPlan is doing something weird). I really have no idea right now.</p>

<p>While I was benchmarking I also decided to benchmark my 1st generation USB drobo with 2x1TB and 2x2TB drives in it. You can see where this going. Performance is atrocious. Glad I use it for backup storage and videos.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2011/05/Drobo_Overlapped_0.5_to_8192_1GB.png">
		<figcaption>Drobo benchmark performance. You didn't think it would be any good, did you? </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dell Inspiron Zino HD and Failure]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2010/02/17/dell-inspiron-zino-hd-and-failure/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-17T14:40:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2010/02/17/dell-inspiron-zino-hd-and-failure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Around work and with friends I've obtained a reputation as the go-to-guy for computer hardware, particular home theater and media center computers. I was really excited about the new Dell Inspiron Zino HD, a tiny little box that can pack a dual core Athlon processor, a couple of gigs of ram, and a decent enough video card to play some games. Starts around $299, and you can get a nicely loaded one for $500. Sounds like a great deal.</p>

<p>A couple of weeks ago I placed an order for an Inspiron Zino HD for my wife and our apartment in Minneapolis. I ordered minor upgrades to make it a bit beefier and faster:</p>

<ul>
<li>AMD Athlon x2 6850</li>
<li>3GB Ram</li>
<li>ATI Radeon HD 4330/512MB RAM video card</li>
<li>320GB hard disk</li>
<li>Dell 1520 802.11 b/g/n wireless card</li>
</ul>


<p>None of these require substantial modifications to the device.  Apparently adding in the video card requires a swap from the standard motherboard to one with an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mobile_PCI_Express_Module">MXM</a> video card slot, but that's it.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2010/02/inspiron-zino-hd.jpg">
		<figcaption>My Former Future HTPC </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>The order was placed on January 31st with an expected delivery date of February 15th thanks to some extra money I paid for expedited shipping.  This was just in time for my monthly visit to Minneapolis where I could set the machine up with Windows 7 Media Center and put it on the wireless network so my wife wouldn't need to worry about a thing. To surprise her I also ordered her an HD HomeRun and a nice Windows Media Center remote from Amazon. Instead of using Hulu for everything, she would be able to record everything and not have to wait until the next day to watch shows. This is a godsend to our relationship where otherwise I know that I can't call her between 8pm and 10pm EST on Thursdays because of "30 Rock" and "The Office".</p>

<p>Toward the middle of last week I started to get concerned.  My order was still listed as "In Production".  On Thursday, the day the machine would have to ship to make it's delivery date.  As expected, however, on Friday the website was updated saying that the order was delayed. On Monday afternoon, more than 72 hours after the order was delayed on the website, I finally got an email telling me the order was delayed.  Apparently the tubes are really clogged at Dell.</p>

<p>Yesterday and today I took some time and investigated how many other people had delays and what my other options for.  Some people were advocating the Dell Studio Slim; it looks promising, but it doesn't ship until the end of March. Wow. Looking around more I found numerous tales of people who ordered their systems as far back as November and still haven't received them:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://en.community.dell.com/forums/p/19310185/19648514.aspx">A retired Librarian's tale on dell.com</a></li>
<li><a href="http://me-and-dee.web.officelive.com/ZinoHDReview.aspx">Leon Lin, who ordered a Zino in November with Blu-Ray and still hasn't received it</a></li>
<li><a href="http://episteme.arstechnica.com/eve/forums/a/tpc/f/67909965/m/920002762041">RobN from ArsTechnica who ordered one for Christmas and found out it would be substantially delayed</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.avsforum.com/avs-vb/showthread.php?t=1202126">Hundreds of posts from AVSForum</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Apparently Dell was insistent on giving 1980's order from TV commercials a good name by shipping products not in 6-8 weeks, but in 12+ weeks. In some cases they were actually in violation of FTC standards for how long it was taking to ship products.  Awesome. I knew I had to do something to stop the pain now.</p>

<p>At first I called Dell just to try and get a refund for my expedited shipping. After about ten minutes I finally reached a human in India who asked me what my problem was. I stated very clearly that my order was delayed and therefore I should get a refund for the difference in shipping costs. I was transferred and put on hold for another 10 minutes until I spoke to a nice lady named Priyanka. Unfortunately, she didn't understand why this would be a problem and said that they could not change my shipping option now that my system was "in production".  I told it had been "in production" for the last two and a half weeks, so I'm sure she could. No dice.</p>

<p>I attempted to figure out what that issue was. Rumors on the webternets indicate that there is a <a href="http://en.community.dell.com/forums/t/19310185.aspx?PageIndex=2#19620350">lack of black lids for this little guy</a>.  Priyanka didn't know about that. I asked if she could change my order to a red lid and if things might ship faster, she said that I'd have to pay the difference in prices. I explained that if I didn't get the red lid that I'd probably just cancel the order, so either they eat the couple of bucks difference in plastic prices, or lose everything from the order.</p>

<p>As you can imagine, Dell chose the latter. Even though my order was "in production" she still allowed me to cancel it. I asked if I would get an email about it, she had no idea what I meant. Finally she said that my order status page would be updated. At the end of the call she asked for my email, I told them that they had it. She said they wanted to update it. I told them my email was firstname at lastname dot net.  She didn't get it. So I spelled it out p-a-t-r-i-c-k-@-w-a-g-s-t-r-o-m-.-n-e-t.  She explained that my email address should end in hotmail.com or gmail.com. At this point I wanted to cry. I asked them what they had, she read off patrick@wagstrom.net and insisted that it could not be a valid email address. Just shoot me. I thanked her for her time, informed her that the information was correct and hung up.</p>

<p>Five minutes later I had placed an order for a <a href="http://www.newegg.com/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16883103237">larger, faster, and slightly noisier machine from NewEgg</a>. For $200 in savings and not having to deal with Dell, I can deal with a little bit of noise. Unfortunately, the full review won't arrive until the end of March when I'm back in Minneapolis.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
