<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | My Delusional Dream]]></title>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-12T20:51:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Wagstrom]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Review of 2011 Personal Development Goals]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2012/01/03/a-review-of-2011-personal-development-goals/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-03T12:29:07-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2012/01/03/a-review-of-2011-personal-development-goals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In January 2011 I made my <a href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2011/01/01/2011-personal-development-goals/">2011 Personal Development Goals</a> public. In the spirit of complete transparency, here's my scorecard of how I did on my quest to accomplish these goals. I'm not being quite as hard on these goals as I was on my <a href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2012/01/02/a-review-of-open-source-predictions-for-2011/">2011 Open Source predictions</a>, but I'm still trying to be honest with myself.</p>

<h3>Academic</h3>

<ul>
<li><strong>Submit papers to FSE, CSCW, and ICSE</strong> - Two out of three. Didn't get anything off for ICSE.</li>
<li><strong>Submit at least one journal paper</strong> - Nope, but I'm getting close on two fronts. Still, I didn't make it.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Physical</h3>

<p>These are all covered in detail on my <a href="http://twentysixandtwo.wordpress.com/2011/12/30/running-goals-for-2011-looking-back/">Review of 2011 running goals on my running blog</a>. I've shortened the answers here.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Run a mile in under 5:50</strong> - Nope. 6:10 was the best I could manage.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Run a marathon in under 3:50</strong> - Nope, I got close. 3:57:45 in New York.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Bench press my own weight</strong> - Utter failure. I don't recall ever really trying.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Get down to 170 lbs</strong> - I came close. 172ish was my best. I'm considerably over that right now.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Barefoot/Vibram race of 10k or more</strong> - Not only did I do a 10k in my Vibrams, I set a PR in the race too. After a bad experience going completely barefoot, I think I'll stick with the Vibrams in the future.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Run to and from work at least five times</strong> - Never even tried this.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Personal</h3>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Release a new and interesting Open Source project</strong> - I kinda did this with the release of <a href="https://github.com/pridkett/govscigraph">GovSciGraph</a> but that was something that came out of a work project and not out of my own projects. Therefore I'm going to say that I missed this goal. Also, no one seems interested in GovSciGraph, so it's not much of an Open Source project.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Visit a new country</strong> - I'm not certain if Hong Kong and Macau count as they're only kinda countries and I had previously traveled to China. I did, however, visit Hungary, Slovakia, and spend far more than my previous eight hours in Austria.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Read two "<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/arts/bigread/top100.shtml">Classics</a>"</strong> - Success. From the BBC's list I read "Pride and Prejudice", "Animal Farm", "Winnie the Pooh", and "Alice in Wonderland". Combined with a decent stack of other books this was a decent book reading year for me. I look forward to reading more of these "Classics" in the coming year.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Win at least two of my existing video games before buying any new ones</strong> - I've been vacillating on this one. I haven't bought any console games this year, but I did get some new ones. I traded my DS Lite and games for some Wii games during the summer, which is kinda like buying new games. I got a couple of games for Christmas, but I didn't buy them, so I don't think they count against my score. However, I'm going to have to say I failed at this. Stupid iOS games and <a href="http://www.appshopper.com/">AppShopper.com</a> showing me when games go on sale. While you can't "win" many of these iOS games, I certainly bought many games and this will keep me occupied for a long time. Maybe sometime this year I can finally win Planescape: Torment, Arcanum, and Fable 2. Also, stop buying iOS games.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Spend less than $60 at the cafeteria at work</strong> - 100% success. I never bought lunch at the cafeteria. I bought a few cookies and coffee/tea for some visitors, but according to Mint.com I only spent $24.32 at the cafeteria this year. This is a good thing because the food went significantly downhill from what I've heard.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Do four "10 day trials"</strong> - I tried going vegetarian for ten days, but I had to travel after seven and gave it up. My wife isn't too thrilled with this idea of screwing with my body. I'm not certain if I'll repeat it again this year.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><del>Cook Creme Brulee</del></strong> - accomplished on 12/27/2010. That's what getting a Creme Brulee torch for Christmas will do for you.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Breaking Bad Habits</h3>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Only 12 sodas in the year</strong> - No so good. I didn't count, but with 78 flights over the past year I'm pretty certain I was well over my limit.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Only 6 packs of Starburst in the year</strong> - Complete and utter failure. Target keeps on selling the monster bags for $2 each. Do you have any idea how easy it is to eat a monster bag of Starburst? Furthermore, do you have any idea of what this does to your gut? It's not pretty. Fortunately, the vending machines at work no longer stock Starburst.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Only 3 visits to McDonalds in the year</strong> - I think I might have been close on this. I can only remember three times, and that includes numerous trips through airports. I'm going to say I succeeded in this one.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Overall I didn't do horrible, but it's clear that most of goals where I tried to rid myself of bad habits or be more productive were failures. I'm either setting the bar too high or I'm not doing enough to maintain accountability with those goals. In any case, I should revisit my strategy. Sometime in the next few days I'll post my goals for 2012. I'm still working on them for right now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guilty Pleasures...]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2011/04/18/guilty-pleasures/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-18T19:05:59-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2011/04/18/guilty-pleasures</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm 32, married, a professional scientist, and I have a confession to make. I play video games. Worse, I feel guilty about playing games. I often feel so guilty that it saps much of the guy from the game, turning it into some perverse drudgery where I feel obligated to keep on playing so I can say I actually beat the game. In other words, the guilt that I get from playing video games is so great that it turns every game into an <a href="http://majicjungle.com/blog/261/">obligation game like Farmville</a>.</p>

<p>I shouldn't say that it's always this way with games. I can sit down and play Hydro Thunder for 15 minutes after work and enjoy it. Until I realize that I should be doing something else, like <a href="http://twentysixandtwo.wordpress.com/">training for a marathon</a>, reading a paper, or writing some code.  What's interesting is that nowhere in that list of alternative things is something that is related to family. It could be because I don't live with my wife right now and I don't have kids. But I believe it's a symptom of something else.</p>

<p>Between my masters and doctorate degrees I spent a little over seven years in graduate school. Seven years in which every waking moment was supposed to be optimized for work. Now, I admit that I didn't do that. In fact, I had one hell of time during graduate school. It was a hell of a lot of fun. However, graduate school has no concept of work life balance. There always
is more work you can be doing. You know that there is always some paper you should be reading or writing, a presentation that could be created, or a new skill to be obtained. Even if your advisor doesn't drill that into your head (and thankfully I had amazing advisors) there are always other students who do.</p>

<p>Of course, it should have gotten better after grad school, but then I left to work for a company that gave up on the concept of work life balance and now talks about work life integration. This is largely a side effect of working with people all over the world. Phone calls from 9-11pm with China are hardly unusual. Nor is a 7:30am meeting with Israel. On the plus side I get the
flexibility I need to travel and can sleep in on days when I don't have early morning meetings, but it still remains that during my waking hours I always have a sense of guilt about things I should be doing. In turn this guilt ends up sapping the fun away from things that should be fun.</p>

<p>The question that I need to answer is this, which is the correct behavior? Believing that video games are fun? Realizing there is always more to do? Or perhaps some other choice?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2011 Personal Development Goals]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2011/01/01/2011-personal-development-goals/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-01T00:01:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2011/01/01/2011-personal-development-goals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I hate the concept of New Year's Resolutions with an utter passion. It's arbitrary for people to pick a single day and decide to change everything. Some people might call these resolutions, I call these personal development goals.  None of these are dramatic changes from things that I already do, or should be doing. Rather, this set of goals will help keep me on track for 2011.</p>

<h3>Academic</h3>

<ul>
<li>Submit papers to FSE, CSCW, and ICSE</li>
<li>Submit at least one journal paper</li>
</ul>


<h3>Physical</h3>

<p>These and a few more are covered in <a href="http://twentysixandtwo.wordpress.com/2010/12/31/running-goals-for-2011-looking-forward/">a post about 2011 goals on my marathon blog</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li>Run a mile in under 5:50</li>
<li>Run a marathon in under 3:50</li>
<li>Bench press my own weight</li>
<li>Get down to 170 lbs</li>
<li>Barefoot/Vibram race of 10k or more</li>
<li>Run to and from work at least five times</li>
</ul>


<h3>Personal</h3>

<ul>
<li>Release a new and interesting Open Source project</li>
<li>Visit a new country</li>
<li>Read two "<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/arts/bigread/top100.shtml">Classics</a>"</li>
<li>Win at least two of my existing video games before buying any new ones</li>
<li>Spend less than $60 at the cafeteria at work</li>
<li>Do four "10 day trials"</li>
<li><del>Cook Creme Brulee</del> - accomplished on 12/27/2010. That's what getting a Creme Brulee torch for Christmas will do for you.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Breaking Bad Habits</h3>

<ul>
<li>Only 12 sodas in the year</li>
<li>Only 6 packs of Starburst in the year</li>
<li>Only 3 visits to McDonalds in the year</li>
</ul>


<p>The most annoying thing about setting such personal development goals is that I haven't been able to find a good tool to track these goals.  If anyone knows of one feel free to post it in the comments.  I'll revisit these goals at the end of the 2011 calendar year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iron April 2009]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/04/02/iron-april-2009/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-02T12:00:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/04/02/iron-april-2009</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm officially on the hook for competing in <a href="http://kevinhaugh.blogspot.com/2008/03/iron-april-2008-athletes.html">Iron April 2009</a>.  It's an interesting event organized by a real Ironman, <a href="http://kevinhaugh.blogspot.com/">Kevin Haugh</a>, that takes loads of folks who normally don't triathalons and convinces them to do the distance of an Ironman over the course of the month of April.  It's an informal sort of competition where you're motivated by the other folks who are also trying to accomplish the same thing.  There's not prize for being the first person to finish, other than knowing that you managed to complete Iron April.  Each person has a page where they post their updates and progress.  I'll be posting little short blurbs <a href="http://kevinhaugh.blogspot.com/2005/01/patrick-wagstrom.html">here</a>.  In addition, sometime soon I'll also create some sort of widget that I can use to post my overall progress on the sidebar of the blog.</p>

<p>I'm fairly certain that the running will be no problem.  Most weeks I break 26.2 miles without the extra motivation.  If I don't hit 26.2 miles this month it will be because I've done something stupid and injured myself.  Swimming just requires me to go to the pool a couple of times and get a few hours of swimming in, not a big deal when you're on a university campus.  The difficult thing will be biking.  I'm going to start biking to and from school every day, which gives me about 4 miles along the bike trails.  I'll also have to do some longer bike routes on the weekend or on my off days from running.</p>

<p>In any case, it looks fun and is the first baby steps toward me eventually doing a real Ironman race.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm Working at IBM Research]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2007/07/15/working-at-ibm/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-15T00:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2007/07/15/working-at-ibm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After my last post I got a few emails from folks saying that they didn't know what I was up to now-a-days.  I'm currently working for IBM Research in Hawthorne, NY (just outside of NYC), in their IT Governance group. In other words, I'm doing similar things at IBM that I've been doing for my thesis research for the last few years.  I'll be in the NYC area until at least the end of August.  If you're visiting, let me know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
