<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/resources/xslt/page.xsl"?>
<my:doc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2000/10/XMLSchema-instance"
	xmlns:my="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/xml/webpage/1"
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
	title="Pat's crappy bandwidth explanation page"
	style="default"
	revision="$$">

<my:infobox title="Why can't you link to that image?">
<p>
If you're here it's probably because you saw this nasty graphic on a page:
</p>
<center>
<img src="/resources/images/bandwidthThief.png" width="400" height="151" alt="bandwidth thief graphic"/>
</center>
<p>
Odd's are that it's not directly your fault, so I wouldn't be too concerned.  But here's a bit of
an explanation.
</p>
<p>
This site is run as a private sort of hobby for myself, my wife, and a few other family members.  Being
as I'm broke, I just run it off my comcast cable modem.  Occassionaly someone on a higher traffic message
board will find a picture of my site and link to it in a posting.  This causes many, many people to view
this image, using my bandwidth, slowing my own connection, and does not let the viewer know the context or the
source of the image.  As far as web-etiquette goes, this is
considered to be very rude and also doesn't follow the BY-NC-SA license that I have on my works.  So,
to conserve my bandwidth, I've resorted to checking referers.
</p>
<p>
If you got this graphic, then your referer wasn't allowed.  But don't fear.  If its a legitimate site,
email me and I'll add your site to list of sites that hotlink to images.  Here's the current list of
sites that can hotlink (may be slightly out of date):
</p>
<pre>[blank referer string]
bloglines.com
google.com
wm-eddie.info
wplug.org
xml.mfd-consult.dk
chameleonreader.com
</pre>
</my:infobox>

<my:links>
	<my:link name="home" url="/"/>
	<my:link name="resume" url="/resume/"/>
	<my:link name="photos" url="/photos/"/>
	<my:link name="weblog" url="/weblog/"/>
	<my:link name="wedding" url="/wedding/"/>
</my:links>
</my:doc>
