<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: bibtexml | My Delusional Dream]]></title>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/blog/categories/bibtexml/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-12T20:51:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Wagstrom]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting Over]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2004/02/19/two/"/>
    <updated>2004-02-19T22:46:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2004/02/19/two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came to the realization that the current user interface will not be suitable
for what I want it to do.  Also, the entire project had become spaghetti
code becuase of using GLADE for everything.  So with that being said, I started
over on writing my BibTeXML editor today.  It uses glade for some stuff right
now, but that will probably be completely removed in the near future.  PyGTK
makes it easy enough that you really don't need glade.  Anyway, so instead
of the notebooks for each of the views, I'm going to have a notebook for each
file that is open.  Within each file that is open you'll be able to search for
authors, entries etc and also edit them.  Odds are the thing will end up looking
a lot like EndNote by the time I'm done.  I guess that's not a bad thing,
but hopefully it won't look like an alien on my desktop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BibTeXML Editor]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2004/01/11/editor/"/>
    <updated>2004-01-11T22:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2004/01/11/editor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This weekend I've been learning how to do GUI programming in Python with PyGTK.
I've been working on an editor for BibTeXML so you don't always need to type all
the fields by hand.  This is what I've got going so far:</p>

<p><img src="/resources/images/blog/bibteXMLeditor-20040111.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>It's only the people editing that works right now, and even that isn't 100% yet, still
a few tweaks required like auto updating the list of people to the right and being
able to add people to the file.  But the nifty thing is that XML is generated as
you go, which is pretty cool.  I just wish that someone (read: NOT ME) cranked out
a custom widget for GTK that was an XML viewing widget, preferably linked with libxml2
or something like that.  I'm sure I could do it in python, but I don't want to take
the time now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[bibTeXML]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2004/01/07/one/"/>
    <updated>2004-01-07T01:37:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2004/01/07/one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As if I really needed another project that I will only half finish, today I started to muck around with bibTeXML because I wanted something more powerful than the standard bibTeX setup.  Well, I've done some nifty hacking with my mad XSLT skills and got it so it can do cross references on names of authors for when authors show up multiple times.  Right now it just renders to an HTML document, .bib format is next.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
