<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: freedom | My Delusional Dream]]></title>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/blog/categories/freedom/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-12T20:51:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Wagstrom]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do the new TSA AIT body scanners hurt more than they help?]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2010/11/24/do-the-tsa-new-ait-body-scanners-hurt-more-than-they-help/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-24T13:57:03-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2010/11/24/do-the-tsa-new-ait-body-scanners-hurt-more-than-they-help</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Important</h2>

<p>This report and analysis is still in the draft stage.  I'm open to new data, criticisms about my model, grammatical/writing fixes, and suggestions about how to make it better. There are three ways to leave me feedback.  You can leave a comment at the end of this post, post a comment on this <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/OperationGrabAss/comments/eb8s3/hi_reddit_i_did_the_math_and_found_that_tsa/">thread on Reddit</a>, or <a href="http://www.google.com/recaptcha/mailhide/d?k=01d_KRRG_6LhPRiTD9fC4Tjw==&amp;c=MyGA9SW3_9oN5pJPqJPrpR55FWn40q7KpXUM4MUHXoY=">email me directly</a>.</p>

<h2>Pending Improvements</h2>

<p>Thanks to everyone on Reddit, Facebook, and folks in the comments who provided useful feedback.  Here's a preliminary list of items that I'll address in a revision:</p>

<ul>
<li>Better display of graphs: On the cumulative probability graphs, draw some light lines to show the 10/90 window and the median so individuals are better able to see where these values actually lie.  Also, present an additional graph that shows the distribution of all events to make it obvious what the most likely outcome is.</li>
<li>Non-Normality of Terrorist Attacks: Using the expected value for terrorist attacks is somewhat misleading.  A single successful attack can kill hundreds of people.  Instead, I'll write some code to do event based modeling with four different scenarios: 1) Destruction of a cargo airliner (minimal fatalities), 2) Partial destruction of an aircraft (along the lines of a minor/major explosive decompression, like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aloha_Airlines_Flight_243">Aloha Airlines flight 243</a>, 3) Complete destruction of a medium - large jet with total loss of life, 4) Major event with multiple cascading destruction and significant ground fatalities.</li>
<li>Driving vs Flying: I probably over-estimated the number of people opting to drive -- it's clear that the general public doesn't see these things as a major issue (at least that's the TSA said, of course, many AIT scanners were off on the day before Thanksgiving).  More likely this should be between 0.25% and 1.0%.  The length of trips should also be better modeled to something like a triangular distribution between with low, most common, and high values of 200, 400, and 700 miles respectively. Even with these numbers, the story will most likely remain the same, the scanners are scaring people away from a safer form of transit in favor of a riskier one.</li>
<li>Subtraction of Other Risks for Drivers: Drivers have slightly lower risk in some areas than flyers, largely because of no radiation exposure at altitude and no risk of non-violent passenger incidents. It's going to make a small difference, but should be included for intellectual honesty.</li>
</ul>


<h1>Executive Summary</h1>

<p>The deployment by the <a href="http://www.tsa.gov/">TSA</a> of advanced imaging technology (AIT) consisting of backscatter x-ray and millimeter wave detection devices when combined with the new enhanced pat-down procedures has the potential to reduce violent passenger incidents (aka, terrorist attacks on airplanes).  Given the current deployment levels of AIT scanners, these scanners will over a long time horizon only save approximately 2.4 lives a year, while inducing 3.4 incidents of fatal cancer per year over the same period.  Even more troubling is the increase in fatalities as people choose to drive when faced with the possible option of an intrusive enhanced pat-down, which can result in a median of 189 additional roadway fatalities a year.  All together this means that while the AIT program reduces the incidence of a low likelihood,  high risk and high profile terrorist attack, it induces a median of 190.7 deaths across other parts of American society.  Based on this data alone, the AIT will never be able to save more lives than it costs and the program should be considered a failure and stopped immediately.</p>

<h1>Introduction and Background</h1>

<p>The last few weeks has seen absolute uproar over the new TSA advanced imaging technology (AIT) body scanners. In a nutshell, these devices, which utilize two different technologies allow TSA screeners to see underneath a persons clothing without the need for them to actually remove their clothing.  In fact, as we've seen, trying to be helpful to the TSA and <a href="http://www.signonsandiego.com/news/2010/nov/21/gun-crusader-strips-down-shorts-hauled-out-san-die/">removing your clothing is grounds for arrest</a> (or being told to <a href="http://www.boingboing.net/2010/11/21/my-tsa-stripdown-vid.html">put on a jacket if you're a porn star</a>). Concern over these devices comes in multiple different forms: privacy over the use of the images, radiation exposure from backscatter x-ray scanners, and concern over the invasiveness of the new enhanced pat-down procedures for individuals who chose to opt out of the AIT technology or who set off the traditional metal detector too many times.  I believe that all of these are legitimate concerns, however they are far beyond the scope of my expertise.</p>

<p>While there are many questions surrounding AIT, including which airports will be getting them next and what will happen in congress, one thing that I haven't seen is a robust analysis of the costs and risks involved in deploying the scanners across the country.  In this post, I'm going to put the <a href="http://www.epp.cmu.edu/">non-computer science part of my Ph.D.</a> to work and walk through a pretty simple model that allows us to get a first order estimate of the number of lives saved or lost as a result of the AIT body scanners.  In a future post I'll go through some of the math on the dollar costs of the body scanners.</p>

<p>Firstly, there is a ton of uncertainty in the science of these scanners and the knowledge of how the public will react.  The fact is that the backscatter x-ray machines do emit radiation, although at very low levels.  The other type of machine, millimeter wave, does not emit radiation. Also, we're uncertain about how effective these machines are. They're only deployed at a fraction of airports and not all passengers need to go through them.  Even those that go through the scanners cannot be considered 100% effective at stopping a terrorist attack.  Mainly because of well known deficiencies in the scanners, such as their inability to scan body cavities and the fact that <a href="http://www.consumertraveler.com/columns/tsa-myths-and-facts">PETN sewn into the waistband of underwear will not show up on a scanner</a>. Furthermore, the public's reaction to these devices is unknown -- will people actually fly less because of the risk of going through a scanner or enhanced pat-down? What all this means is that we can't just create a simple set of equations for the model and get a single answer. Instead we need to think in terms of uncertainty and distributions.</p>

<p>There are a variety of great tools that can help us creates models with uncertainty.  Notable is <a href="http://www.lumina.com/ana/whatisanalytica.htm">Analytica</a> from <a href="http://www.lumina.com/">Lumina Decision Systems</a>. Other systems exist, such as Crystal Ball, and a component developed by my team at work, Financier.  As a <a href="http://www.cmu.edu/">CMU</a> student I had access to <a href="http://www.lumina.com/ana/whatisanalytica.htm">Analytica</a>, which would have been perfect for this, but my license expired after I received my doctorate. Financier might have worked, but I wanted to make sure that I'm 100% clear this analysis was done on my personal time and the opinions of this document do not reflect those of my employer.  No company software or hardware was used.</p>

<p>Instead, I took the basic premises that I needed to know and wrote a very simple simulation engine that handles uncertainty in <a href="http://www.python.org/">Python</a>.  You can <a href="https://github.com/pridkett/TSASimulation">check all of the code from GitHub</a>.  The code documents all of the input variables along with their sources and shows the complete set of equations for the output.  If you've got Python and the <a href="http://pyparsing.wikispaces.com/">pyparsing library</a> installed on your system, you should be good to download and run the simulation.  Stats and graphs were created in <a href="http://www.r-project.org/">R</a>; the script for their generation is included in the archive.</p>

<h1>Model Inputs</h1>

<p>For each of the model inputs, the best information possible was collected.  I should note, that I'm not an expert on radiation exposure or terrorism, but I do have quite a bit of psychology background and know how to dig at and critically evaluate numbers.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Value of a Human Life:</strong> $6.9M
<strong>Source:</strong> EPA 2008</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Risk of Dying from a Violent Passenger Incident:</strong> 22 in 1 Billion (per flight)
<strong>Source:</strong> <a href="http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2010/01/nate_silver_on.html">Bruce Schneier's Analysis of Nate Silver's Numbers</a>
I added uncertainty to make this a normal distribution with mean of 22 in 1 billion and standard deviation of 3 in 1 billion.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Passenger Enplanements:</strong> 621,000,000
<strong>Source:</strong> <a href="http://www.transtats.bts.gov/">http://www.transtats.bts.gov/</a>
This number includes only domestic passengers.  I added uncertainty to create a normal distribution of 10 million passengers a year.  I acknowledge that international traffic increases this, but I haven't thought about how to deal with it yet.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>AIT Success Rate:</strong> Uniformly distributed between 0.50 and 0.80
<strong>Source: </strong>My own estimate.
I'm trying to be optimistic about the success of these devices.  We know there are multiple things they can't pick up, like PETN sewn into clothing, so they'll never be 100%.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Percentage of Passengers with AIT Screening:</strong> Uniformly distributed 17% and 40%
<strong>Source: </strong> <a href="http://boardingarea.com/blogs/flyingwithfish/2010/11/23/will-you-encounter-a-tsa-whole-body-scanner-statistically-no/">Steve Frischling contacted the TSA to get the full counts of checkpoints with AIT scanners.</a>
I added uncertainty to this model.  Frischling's estimate of 17% is based on uniform passenger distribution across checkpoints.  I assume that passengers are larger airports are more likely to experience them. Therefore, it may be up to 40% of all passengers who have AIT screening as an option.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Percentage of AIT Devices that are Backscatter:</strong> Uniformly distributed between 30 and 75%
<strong>Source:</strong> <a href="http://www.flyertalk.com/forum/travel-safety-security/1138014-complete-list-airports-whole-body-imaging-advanced-imaging-technology-scanner.html">This thread on FlyerTalk tracks the distribution of the devices and their classification.</a>
However, there have been numerous instances when individuals were mistaken about the type of device and had to update the document.  Therefore, while the page looks about 50/50, I added uncertainty.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Passenger Exposure per Backscatter Screening:</strong> Uniformly distributed between 0.20µSv and 0.80µSv
<strong>Source:</strong> The <a href="http://blog.tsa.gov/2009/11/response-to-oops-backscatter-x-ray.html">TSA claims</a> backscatter machines max out at below the 0.25µSv limit set by the government.  This claim is countered by the work of<a href="http://www.public.asu.edu/~atppr/RPD-Final-Form.pdf"> Peter Rez at Arizona State University who found they may have a dose of as much as 0.80µSv</a>.  This also does not address recent comments by <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-1290527/Airport-body-scanners-deliver-radiation-dose-20-times-higher-thought.html">David Brenner of Columbia who believes that the approximately 1:20 people with a specific genetic mutation may be particularly sensitive</a>.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Risk of Fatal Cancer per µSv of Exposure</strong>: 1/12.5 Million
<strong>Source:</strong> <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/fovak/health-effects-of-radiation-exposure-presentation">Slide 76 of this presentation</a>
The presentation indicates that even a small dose of radiation may cause fatal cancer and that the response is roughly linear.  I extrapolated from the lowest level of radiation exposure on chart 76.  If someone has a better set of data for this, I'll gladly take it. I added uncertainty to make this a normal distribution with a mean of 1/12.5 million and standard deviation of 1/125 million.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Fight Distance:</strong> 500 miles
<strong>Source</strong>: My own estimate
The average distance for which an individual would be willing to drive over taking a flight. I based this on my cutoff line.  Admittedly, I've driven from Pittsburgh to Austin, TX in one shot and have routinely driven 18 hours in a day before.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Percentage of Passengers Driving:</strong> Uniformly distributed between 0.5% and 5%
<strong>Source:</strong> My own estimate, based loosely off various non-scientific polls.
I actually believe that this number skews more toward the lower end.  If anyone can come up with a better value, let me know.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Fatalities per Mile of Driving:</strong> 1.13/100 Million Miles
<strong>Source:</strong> <a href="http://www-fars.nhtsa.dot.gov/Main/index.aspx">http://www-fars.nhtsa.dot.gov/Main/index.aspx</a>
Because this number is likely to fluctuate some each year, although it has generally been going down, I've modeled this as a normal with a mean of 1.13/100 Million and standard deviation of 0.1/100 Million Miles.</p></li>
</ul>


<h1>Model</h1>

<p>In brief, the model estimates the number of additional lives saved or lost because of AIT screening technology.  Lives can be saved by a reduction in the number of fatalities from violent passenger incidents. Lives can be lost by an increase in the number of people driving and an increase in fatal cancers because of backscatter radiation.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Number of Passengers Driving:</strong> Passenger Enplanements * Percentage of Passengers Driving
This is how man additional people will be on the road because of opting out of flying altogether.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Number New Driving Fatalities:</strong> Number of Passengers Driving * Flight Distance * 2 * Fatalities per Mile
The distance is multiplied by two here because passengers will need to drive both directions to their destination.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Expected VPI Fatalities:</strong> Risk of Dying from a Violent Passenger Incident * Passenger Enplanements
This is the current baseline number of fatalities expected in a given year.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Expected AIT VPI Fatalities:</strong> Risk of Dying from a Violent Passenger Incident * (1 - AIT Success Rate) * Passenger Enplanements * Percentage of Passengers with AIT Screening + Risk of Dying from a Violent Passenger Incident * Passenger Enplanements * (1 - Percentage of Passengers with AIT Screening)
AIT scanners are only effective where they are used.  This model assumes that the risk of a passenger initiating a VPI has not changed for those passengers not going through AIT.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Expected Cancer Fatalities:</strong> Passenger Enplanements * Percentage of Passengers with AIT Screening * Percentage of AIT Devices that are Backscatter * Passenger Exposure per Backscatter Screening * Risk of Cancer per &amp;microSv of Exposure
As there is no safe level of radiation exposure, even a small amount can cause cancer.  Here we assume that only those passengers who are exposed to AIT backscatter screening are subject to an increase in their cancer risk.  We do not take into account the inherent increase in radiation from flying as that doesn't change. For purposes of simplicity, we also ignore the number of individuals who choose to drive.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Increase in Fatalities due to AIT:</strong> Number New Driving Fatalities + Expected Cancer Fatalities - (Expected VPI Fatalities - Expected AIT VPI Fatalities)
The total number of new deaths represented in the model minus the expected benefit from AIT.</p></li>
</ul>


<h1>Model Outcomes</h1>

<p>The model was run through 10000 iterations to produce a range of outcomes.  First, we'll start with the expected current number of fatalities from violent passenger incidents.  The skies over the United States have been safe from these incidents since 9/11, so this may be overstating the effect. According to my model the median number of passenger fatalities from VPIs on domestic flights is about 13.7 a year, with a 10/90 confidence window of 11.3-16.1 fatalities a year.  <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boeing_737">A Boeing 737 seats around 162 passengers</a>, so this means one VPI resulting in total loss of all passengers on a Boeing 737 sized plane ever 12-13 years.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2010/11/expected_vpi_fatalities.png">
		<figcaption>Expected Fatalities from Violent Passenger Incidents (VPIs) </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>With the introduction of the AIT devices at their current deployment levels, the median expected number of fatalities from VPIs is down to 11.1 a year, with a 10/90 confidence window of 9.0-13.3 fatalities a year.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2010/11/expected_ait_vpi_fatalities.png">
		<figcaption>Expected Fatalities from VPI with AIT in Place </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>It's quickly apparent there there is little difference between these values.  With AIT there is a median improvement of 2.44 fatalities a year, and even in the best case out of the 10,000 simulations only 6.2 additional lives were saved per year.  From a purely monetary perspective, using the EPA's value of $6.9M/life, the AIT project saves $16.84M a year.  I'm almost certain that the program will cost more than from a strict dollar perspective.</p>

<p>Next, lets examine the increased risk of cancer from these devices.  It's believed that any exposure to radiation, no matter how small the dose, increases the chance of cancer.  The TSA has pointed out that under their specifications, backscatter x-ray machines emit about the same amount of radiation as two minutes of flying time (about 0.2µSv).  However, as stated, physics professor Peter Rez has calculated that the likely exposure from a functioning machine is much greater. Using the data from Professor Rez along with known exposure guidelines and the uncertainty in the model, we see there is a median of 3.4 additional cancer fatalities per year, and a 10/90 confidence window of 1.5 to 6.3. The maximum number of new cancer fatalities 11.6/yr. This increase in cancer alone outweighs the median number of lives saved from AIT scanning.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2010/11/expected_cancer_ait_fatalities.png">
		<figcaption>Expected Fatalities from Cancer as a Result of Radiation From Backscatter X-Rays </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>However, there is a slightly more insidious and much more dangerous factor in play.  The mere presence of AIT technology in airports and the possible consequences of an enhanced pat-down will lead some to choose to drive rather than fly.  While there have been some reports that show that as many as 20% [citation needed] of people will reconsider flying because of the enhanced pat-down, I considered the estimates to be far lower.  In my model, the median number of people driving was about 17,000,000 with a 10/90 confidence window of 5,800,000 to 28,500,000.  These numbers may seem a little high, but that's only about 2% of flights being exchanged for a drive of around 500 miles.  Roughly equivalent to a family deciding to drive from Chicago to Minneapolis for Christmas.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2010/11/expected_passengers_driving.png">
		<figcaption>Expected Number of Passengers Choosing to Drive instead of Fly </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Unfortunately, driving is a much riskier endeavor than flying.  In fact, you're more likely to be killed driving to the airport than you are on a plane. Of these people making 1000 mile long round trips, it's likely that we'll see about 189 new fatalities with 10/90 confidence window of 65.6 to 321.3 fatalities.  This is a grim picture, indeed.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2010/11/expected_driving_fatalities.png">
		<figcaption>Expected Fatalities from Passengers Choosing to Drive Instead of Flying </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Finally, we can take the complete picture; the benefit of the AIT machines versus the increased deaths from driving and cancer and see the total increase in fatalities.  In this case, it's not pretty at all.  The use of AIT machines and enhanced pat-downs, when combined with their associated stigma can be expected to cause an additional 190 deaths a year with 10/90 confidence window 67 to 323.  That's the equivalent of all the passengers on a 737 and then some EVERY YEAR as a result of the AIT scanning devices.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2010/11/expected_ait_fatality_increase.png">
		<figcaption>Expected Increase in Fatalities as a Result of AIT Scanning </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<h1>Shortcomings</h1>

<p>One of the problems with pinpointing deaths is that massive deaths at the same time have a significantly greater impact on public perception than a large amount of distributed deaths that aren't always directly attributable.  For example, emissions from coal fired power plants kill significant numbers of people and yet most people are much more scared of nuclear plants because of their potential for an extremely high risk, yet low probability event.  When these events happen react in such a way that the impact is magnified.  More directly, the 9/11 terrorist attacks caused tens of thousands of Americans to cancel their travel plans and businesses to delay investment, which contributed to sending a shaky economy into recession.  This despite the fact that the number of people killed in the attacks was roughly the same number of people killed in a month in traffic accidents across the country or the number of people killed by cancer and heart disease on a DAILY basis. I have no doubt that even the bombing of a cargo flight, with minimal loss to human life, will have a significant and detrimental effect to the American economy, which this simulation cannot model.</p>

<p>This model also does little to address the costs of the screening.  There is not only the cost of the screening devices, but also training of employees, reconfiguration of checkpoints, loss of time for travelers, and treatment for cancer induced by backscatter x-ray.  A robust model would include these, but there is little doubt that the result will remain the same.</p>

<h1>Conclusion</h1>

<p>The overall risk of deploying AIT scanners is significant given their potential benefit.  An median increase of 190 deaths per year can be expected as the result of increases in cancer from screening and increased road fatalities from people opting out of flying and driving to their destination.  From a pure human life perspective, the AIT proposition is a failure.  Even discounting the fatalities from driving, at current deployment levels AIT devices can be expected to induce 3.3 additional cases of cancer a year while only saving 2.4 additional lives per year. Elimination of the backscatter devices and replacement with millimeter wave detection devices may prove to be a suitable replacement given these substantial health risks.</p>

<h1>Next Steps</h1>

<p>I still consider this analysis in a draft form.  As I can find better information I'll update the model.  If you have suggestions on ways to improve the analysis please leave them in the comments.  After I feel that this has been properly vetted, I'm going to send this to <a href="http://klobuchar.senate.gov/">my</a> <a href="http://franken.senate.gov/">senators</a> and <a href="http://ellison.house.gov/">congressman</a> -- all of which are generally pretty awesome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What the TSA has is a failure to communicate]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/12/28/what-the-tsa-has-is-a-failure-to-communicate/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-28T09:48:55-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/12/28/what-the-tsa-has-is-a-failure-to-communicate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Christmas day a young Nigerian man boarded a flight from Lagos to Amsterdam and then later boarded a flight from Amsterdam to Detroit.  About an hour outside of Detroit, as the plane was descending over Canadian airspace he decided that his religion would martyr him if he blew up the plane using a slab of pentaerythritol tetranitrate (aka PETN) taped to his crotch.  Unfortunately for him and fortunately for the plane's passengers the igniter failed and he merely started his crotch on fire and probably blew up his testicles.</p>

<p>As expected, the TSA felt a need to respond to yesterday's threat today.  Apparently it is now a threat to have more than one carry on, electronics in the main cabin on international flights, anything in your lap, and to go to the bathroom within one hour of the flight landing. I'll leave the sanity of these for other people.  What I'm interested in is the way that the TSA shared this information.</p>

<p>The primary way that travelers are told to stay up to date on the ever changing regulations regarding flight security is to visit the <a href="http://www.tsa.gov/">TSA home page</a>.  Here's a screen capture of the home page from December 27th, more than 48 hours after the incident on Northwest 253:</p>

<p><img src="/media/2009/12/TSAWebsiteFail.png"></p>

<p>The TSA has a statement on flight 253, but there is nothing about the new flight restrictions, despite the fact that I'm sure that I, and thousands of other people, were concerned about how their flights home may be impacted.</p>

<p>The digerati may have also checked Twitter for information.  The TSA doesn't have an official Twitter feed, but their blog team has a Twitter feed.  Here's a screen capture of the Twitter feed taken at the same time:</p>

<p><img src="/media/2009/12/TSATwitterFail.png"></p>

<p>There is a link to an <a href="http://www.tsa.gov/blog/2009/12/dhs-statement-on-northwest-airlines.html">article on the TSA's blog about Northwest 253</a>, but the article is merely the official statement and contains nothing about the changing regulations.  For more than 48 hours passengers were left to wonder about the changing regulations and how these regulations impact travel in the holiday season. The primary source of the changing regulations was a message on <a href="http://www.aircanada.com/en/news/trav_adv/091226_3.html">Air Canada's web site</a>.</p>

<p>Finally, late on the 27th the actual text of the regulations was finally made available, but not through an easy source on TSA's website.  Instead, we're forced to go to <a href="http://www.elliott.org/blog/full-text-of-sd-1544-09-06-authorizing-pat-downs-physical-inspection/">Christopher Elliott's full text of the directive</a>.</p>

<p>The administration has been quiet on the issue, but I believe that is more by design.  There's no need to send everyone off to Sunday morning talk shows because a terrorist decided to try and blow his own balls off.  What isn't acceptable is the long delay and horrible communication regarding the new restrictions for travelers.  There's lots more that could be written on this, but I'm trying to minimize editorializing in this article.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Antifeatures in Free Software]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/09/15/antifeatures-in-free-software/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-15T16:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2009/09/15/antifeatures-in-free-software</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.fsf.org/">Free Software Foundation</a> has, rightfully in most cases, alerted computer and technology users to the problem of “<a href="http://www.fsf.org/bulletin/2007/fall/antifeatures/">antifeatures</a>“. Briefly, an antifeature is when a program does something to offer a lesser experience that took significant effort to accomplish. Often times antifeatures are used as differentiating elements between different versions of a product. When you buy the lesser version everything is still there, it’s just that there is a small amount of code that disables part of program. Code that had to be written by a software developer and cost money to implement.</p>

<p>Common examples of antifeatures are software packages that arbitrarily the number of remote connections (e.g. <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windowsserver2008/en/us/pricing.aspx">Windows Server</a> and <a href="http://www.apple.com/remotedesktop/">Apple Remote Desktop</a>) and how inexpensive digital cameras automatically process <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raw_image_format">RAW</a> image data to JPEG — the latter is an example from the Free Software Foundation that may not hold up because of the cost in allowing a user to access the image processing pipeline in the middle, although the <a href="http://chdk.wikia.com/">CHDK</a> hackers have made good headway.</p>

<p>With the Free Software Foundation so adamantly anti-antifeature, you can imagine my surprise when I discovered <a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/gnuzilla/">GNU IceCat</a>.  Not only is IceCat a duplication of effort of Debian’s <a href="http://wiki.debian.org/Iceweasel">IceWeasel</a> software — both are versions of <a href="http://www.getfirefox.com/">Mozilla Firefox</a> that lack the registered trademark of the Firefox branding, something that requires a usage agreement (note: IceCat originated before IceWeasel and originally was named IceWeasel, however the name was ceded to Debian when the latter became more dominant and higher profile). To be fair, Mozilla has little choice in this matter. You’re legally obligated to defend a registered trademark or you can lose it — a law that is fundamentally at odds with Free software. However, what is surprising about IceCat is that rather than providing the full access to the plugin ecosystem for Firefox, IceCat has chosen to provide access to only those plugins that are also Free software.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<a href="http://www.getfirefox.com/"><img src="/media/2009/09/firefox.png" alt="Mozilla Firefox" /></a> vs. <a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/gnuzilla/"><img src="/media/2009/09/icecat.png" alt="GNU IceCat" /></a> vs. <a href="http://wiki.debian.org/Iceweasel"><img src="/media/2009/09/iceweasel.png" alt="Debian IceWeasel" /></a>
		<figcaption>It's like there's a nerd fight and no one cares! </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>This is clearly an antifeature. Somewhere out there in Internetland a programmer spent time to code a feature in IceCat that restricts the ability of a user to download all the plugins for Firefox. While this is very much in line with the Free Software Foundation’s stance on having all software be Free, it’s not good from a user choice standpoint, and is clearly an antifeature that is wholly different than the primary reason for the project — avoiding trademark issues with the Firefox branding.</p>

<p>I’m not attempting to say that IceCat is a bad project — I don’t use it, but I can understand why it is there — it serves as a bit of protection should something crazy go on with the trademark agreement for Firefox. Furthermore, the Free Software Foundation is perfectly free to create a parallel plugin ecosystem, but they should be entirely clear about it — in this case Free software isn’t about choice or freedom from licensing agreements, it’s about their ideology and how they can create a tool to enforce their worldview.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Free Software Foundation's Misguided and Misinformed Campaign Against the iPhone 3G]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2008/07/31/fsf-misguided-misinformed-campaign-against-the-iphone3g/"/>
    <updated>2008-07-31T14:20:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2008/07/31/fsf-misguided-misinformed-campaign-against-the-iphone3g</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.fsf.org/">Free Software Foundation</a> has done some truly amazing things for computers.  The creation of Emacs, GCC, most of the standard Linux utilities, and the genesis of the ideas that later created Open Source (although, Stallman despises it), are just a few of the important things they've done.  They generally fight the good fight and make the computer world a better place to be.</p>

<p>However, over the past few years, something seems to have changed within the Free Software Foundation.  With the rise of DRM the Free Software Foundation began to organize vocal protests against systems that enabled content providers to protect their creations -- after all, Free software doesn't need such protections.  <a href="http://blogs.zdnet.com/BTL/?p=3098">Activists in haz-mat suits</a> could be seen at product launches for Windows Vista, at the Virgin Megastore, and lots of other places where they thought they could get attention.  Always handing out little stickers explaining the problems with DRM.  In fact, for a very long time, I've had a <a href="http://thomashawk.com/2006/10/ipod-itunes-drm-defective-by-design.html">defective by design sticker</a> on my laptop.</p>

<p>Of course, this was 2006 and times were very different back then. There weren't any stores to purchase non-DRM'd music, now it seems you can purchase it everywhere, so the whole DRM'd music issue is a bit more moot now.  Instead, the Defective by Design campaign has chosen to focus on any system that enables DRM.  Well, I shouldn't say any system that enables, just some systems -- in particular the iPhone 3G.  In their latest effort, Defective by Design has been actively encouraging people to <a href="http://defectivebydesign.org/apple-challenge">book times at Apple Genius bars to harass employees and customers</a>.  First, let's look at the five claims they make about the iPhone 3G:</p>

<p><strong>1. iPhone completely blocks free software. Developers must pay a tax to Apple, who becomes the sole authority over what can and can’t be on everyone’s phones.</strong></p>

<p>This is partially true.  It does cost money to become an <a href="http://developer.apple.com/iphone/program/">official iPhone developer</a>, but the amount is actually quite small, $99.  There is also the little annoyance of the current <a href="http://www.fuckingnda.com/">NDA on the developer kit</a> that also restricts what developers can do, although it is expected to be lifted soon.  However, it fails on a couple of points.  First, if you're an iPhone developer, you can run any application you develop on your iPhone and those of 4 other people.  Once the beta system comes you'll be able to distribute to 100 other people.  For small scale distribution this is pretty good.  And second, and perhaps bigger, there is always the option of <a href="http://lifehacker.com/398906/jailbreak-iphone-20-with-pwnagetool">jailbreaking your phone</a> to run whatever the heck you want.  If you want to develop other applications, you're more than free to download the <a href="http://thepiratebay.org/tor/4085451/iPhone_unofficial_SDK">iPhone unofficial SDK</a>.  Last year when Bradley Kuhn, former FSF Executive Director, spoke at <a href="http://www.ohiolinux.org/">Ohio LinuxFest</a> he bragged about removing DRM from music, so I'd assume they'd be find with this.</p>

<p><strong>2. iPhone endorses and supports Digital Restrictions Management (DRM) technology.</strong></p>

<p>That's correct, the iPhone supports DRM'd files.  It also supports non-DRM'd files too.  Unlike <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/s/cmp/20080726/tc_cmp/209601121">Yahoo which cut off customers who purchased this music</a>, Apple intends to continue to support them.  Video files are still encumbered, but I don't know of any legal way to get high quality digital video that isn't encumbered.  That's an issue you'll have to take up with the industry, Apple is just ensuring people can use it.  Remember, with music DRM came first, then when it failed, we got open systems.  There is no reason to expect it will be different with movies and TV shows.</p>

<p>Another aspect where the iPhone supports DRM is with iPhone apps.  I'd imagine this is partially necessary to keep people from pirating the apps.  When piracy rates for PC software <a href="http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/53357">may run above 95%</a>, there no reason to assume that people aren't going to pirate software.  Yes, there is DRM there, but it's pretty weak and lets me load the apps on any of the phones on my plan.  Not to mention, it's been shown to be trivial to remove the DRM, although, that currently doesn't let one run the app on another phone.</p>

<p><strong>3. iPhone exposes your whereabouts and provides ways for others to track you without your knowledge.</strong></p>

<p>Complete bullshit.  Whoever wrote this has never touched an iPhone and clearly doesn't realize that every app must ask before it can use your location information.  The only tracking that happens is whatever the carriers and law enforcement people typically use to track folks.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile>	<figure class='center'>
		<img src="/media/2008/07/inetworktest-location.jpg">
		<figcaption>iNetworkTest patiently asks for permission to use your location </figcaption>
	</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p><strong>4. iPhone won’t play patent-and-DRM-free formats like Ogg Vorbis and Theora.</strong></p>

<p>Waah.  Neither will most other things.  If Vorbis and Theora are great from a technical perspective then you'd think you'd see a lot more of them floating around -- but they're not.  Yes, I'm sure that Apple could implement at Theora and Vorbis codec in the iPhone, but I doubt it's worth   their time.  The people who really care about those issues aren't the kind of people who use iPhones to begin with.  Apple is concerned about making the user experience good.  Providing too many options leads to M-x play-vorbis-song.  Not very friendly.</p>

<p><strong>5. iPhone is not the only option. There are better alternatives on the horizon that respect your freedom, don’t spy on you, play free media formats, and let you use free software – like the FreeRunner.</strong></p>

<p>That's somewhat correct.  The FreeRunner, along with with its incomplete and buggy software is now available.  I've played with them -- I tried to make a call with one.  It crashed.  I tried to lock at pictures.  It crashed.  I couldn't check my email with it.  There
weren't any well polished apps for it.  The list goes on.  The FreeRunner may be an option for some people, but it's expensive and has little software.  If I'm trying to get stuff done, that's not a good thing.</p>

<p>Beyond the five points, of which, I've just shown have approximately 2 points of validity, the campaign contains a <a href="http://static.fsf.org/dbd/iphone-action-handout.pdf">questionnaire</a> that you're supposed to use to quiz the Apple genius.  So, lets look at these questions:</p>

<blockquote><p><span>1.</span> Why do all developers have to submit their applications to Apple before they can be loaded onto an iPhone? Most smartphones, including those by OpenMoko, Nokia, RIM, Palm and even Microsoft, allow applications to come from a variety of sources, including free software developers. Free ”as in freedom” software development requires that users and developers be able to share and modify the source code for programs they use. iPhone users are not permitted by Apple to share or load modified versions of programs distributed through the App Store – even when a program’s developer wants users to be able to do this! Apple markets itself as empowering, alternative technology – How does Apple plan to support free software development?</p>

<p>a. Did the Genius understand the issue of free software?</p>

<p>b. Did they admit that other devices allow you to install applications from a variety of sources?</p></blockquote>

<p>I'd like to first point out that this is a couple of issues all muddled together into one.  Apple does allow Free software developers to develop for the iPhone, the WordPress people provide the source code to their app.  Then, all that is standing in your way is the $99 developers fee.  Once you've got that, run Free and Open Source to your hearts content.  The issue is regarding supporting Free software.  Apple has no obligation or business case that would require them to do so.  Their system is based on Open Source which is not free -- if they chose to contribute back they may.  However, allowing just anyone to create an untested unverified app that can brick your cell phone or really whack out the cell network, well, that's not such a great idea.  The FSF needs to realize that the cell network is fundamentally different than a computer network.  A malicious or poorly designed app can easily degrade the shared communication for everyone and rack up lots of bills for you.  This poses a question that I'd like to ask the FSF people: How would Free software benefit the iPhone?</p>

<blockquote><p><span>2.</span> Why does iTunes still contain so much DRM-laden music? Services like Amazon, eMusic, Napster, Rhapsody, Play.com and 7digital are all selling music without DRM. A typical response to this might be that Apple has no option to sell media without DRM, but this is simply untrue. Jobs is the majority shareholder at Disney, and he could insist that its films be DRM-free. Apple should be leading the way to promote DRM-free music, but instead is lagging behind. What is Apple doing to fix this? If it really is the RIAA’s fault, can you tell me specifically what the RIAA said to Jobs when he asked for the ability to sell DRM-free music?</p>

<p> a. Did the Genius understand that Amazon, Rhapsody and Napster, along with many others are supporting DRM free music from the very same labels and artists that Apple is selling, laden with Digital Restrictions Management?</p>

<p>b. Did the Genius understand that DRM is not about rights, but about restrictions? Restricting the people who buy the music and videos from playing them on a variety of devices, like CDs and DVDs. Did the Genius understand that Steve Jobs’ role at Disney could be used to leverage Disney going DRM-free?</p></blockquote>

<p>This one I don't have a solid answer for.  I'd imagine that part of the reason why there are protected tracks has to do with longer term contracts.  Another reason may have to deal with a lack of incentive to change.  In either case, the Genius is unlikely to have this sort of knowledge.  They're NOT your personal Apple PR person, so just deal with it. Point two, I have a bit better response to.  I can understand why individuals would want to protect their content with DRM - especially when some people are so eager to steal your intellectual property.  So in that response, it is about the rights of the producer.  When I create something I should have the right to dictate to some degree who it is used.  That's codified in US Copyright law -- you know, the exclusive right bit.  Yeah, you might want to check that out.  What isn't clearly codified is fair use.  It's a much murkier proposition. Want to change this?  Start by codifying fair use in US law.</p>

<p>With regards to Disney, this is a pretty good point.  Steve could probably push Disney to drop DRM, but there would need to be a business case for it.  He has a fiduciary responsibility to shareholders still -- so, unless you can show me that such a decision would improve Disney's bottom line, then you have no argument.</p>

<blockquote><p><span>3.</span> The iPhone 3G has GPS support. How can users be sure that the GPS cannot be used to track their position, without their permission? When the only thing preventing the GPS from being used is software, and the software in question is known only to Apple, why should users of the iPhone trust Apple?</p>

<p>a. Did the Genius understand why GPS in a device is an issue?</p>

<p>  b. Did the Genius understand why the fact that the iPhone is proprietary is an issue here?</p>

<p>  c. Did the Genius express any kind of apology for this behavior?</p></blockquote>

<p>Once again, seem my previous point regarding their five claims against the iPhone 3G.  This is not an issue.  The software asks before it uses your location.  Every cell phone has some sort of GPS in it that is used for E911 services, therefore every cell phone could be rigged to spy on people.  You're now crossing into conspiracy territory and losing credibility fast.</p>

<blockquote><p><span>4.</span> In ’<a href="http://www.apple.com/hotnews/thoughtsonmusic/">Thoughts on Music</a>’, Steve Jobs said ”it is useful to remember that all iPods play music that is free of any DRM and encoded in ’open’ licensable formats such as MP3 and AAC”. If Steve really wants to see free and open formats, why doesn’t the iPhone play Ogg Vorbis, Ogg Theora video and FLAC? These formats require no licensing costs, and are not encumbered by patents. How does Apple plan to support these formats in future?</p>

<p>a. Did the Genius understand the issue of free formats, such as Ogg Vorbis?</p>

<p>b. Did the Genius give any indication as to Apple’s lack of support for these formats?</p></blockquote>

<p>Let's turn this around, if the Free Software Foundation really supports free and open formats, why don't they let my arbitrarily designed custom bitstream for my handycam shot movie.  It's a documented format that is free and open on the web.  Exactly.  Most people don't care about these issues.  Using Apple stuff is like shopping in the organic food aisle at the super market -- less selection, but the stuff is tasty.  Windows, which supports all those formats through various plugins, is like shopping in a regular supermarket.  If the FSF had their way, we'd be shopping in
post-Katrina looted supermarkets with broken shopping carts -- multimedia doesn't work that well in Linux, maybe the desire to support way too many formats is part of the reason.  Choice isn't always good, especially when those choices really suck.  With regards to FLAC, people who really care about FLAC already have padded rooms with vacuum tube amps and wouldn't dream of listening to their music on something as pedestrian as a personal music player.</p>

<blockquote><p><span>5.</span> Last question. Why can the iPhone 3G only be activated by Apple and AT&amp;T? In the United States, the Register of Copyrights has ruled that consumers have the right to unlock their phones and switch to a different carrier. How does Apple plan to remedy this discrepancy?</p>

<p>a. Did the Genius offer any advice or suggestions in unlocking your iPhone and moving it to another provider?</p>

<p>b. Did the Genius admit that Apple is getting kickbacks from your phone bill in exchange for locking you to a single provider?</p>

<p>c. Did the Genius offer any timeframe for Apple fixing this, despite the Register of Copyrights ruling?</p></blockquote>

<p>The decision the FSF is referring to is the latest set of <a href="http://www.copyright.gov/1201/index.html">DMCA exemptions</a>. You'll notice that they don't require carriers to assist you in unlocking your phone.  The decision merely makes it legal to unlock your phone.  So, FSF people, get cracking and write the software that will allow me to slip in a local SIM card when I go to Greece.</p>

<p>With regards to the other sub points, there is no reason why the Apple rep should provide the information on how to change a carrier.  They've got a contract with AT&amp;T saying that AT&amp;T will be the exclusive carrier.  AT&amp;T is subsidizing the prices of the phones, contributing to advertising, maintaining the infrastructure that makes the phone useful.  This isn't cheap, in fact AT&amp;T has said that they're planning on taking a <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/s/cmp/20080724/tc_cmp/209401147">$720 million dollar hit</a> from subsidizing the iPhone.  That's a huge chunk of change that AT&amp;T is spending to support a piece of Apple hardware.  Also, in the US switching to another provider inherently makes your iPhone suck more as T-Mobile is the only other major GSM carrier in the US and their 3G network <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2008/07/30/t-mobile-3g-service-coming-october-1-to-27-markets/">won't be ready until October 1st</a>, and even then, it's only 27 markets.</p>

<p>With regards to kickbacks, it's well documented that Apple is getting even more kickbacks from AT&amp;T.  Just by purchasing a phone at an Apple store you're causing <a href="http://blogs.barrons.com/techtraderdaily/2008/06/19/apple-oppenheimer-says-att-iphone-subsidy-is-325/">AT&amp;T to pay $100 to Apple</a> for signing up a new customer, on top of the $300 or so that they're subsidizing the purchase price.  However, the older kickback system where Apple got a portion of the monthly bill, is <a href="http://www.thestandard.com/news/2008/06/09/3g-iphone-drops-revenue-sharing-t-apple-due-handset-subsidy">no longer in effect</a>. So, I think that I've been able to go through and show that most of the campaign by the FSF is wrong, or just based on incorrect facts, and on the basis of these incorrect facts they're going into Apple stores and bothering employees who 1) really don't care and 2) have better things to do.  Yeah, way to go FSF, I'm sure you'll find some <a href="http://linuxhaters.blogspot.com/">freetards</a> who will be excited by this, but everyone else sees that you're just being dicks.  Go back to your crappy little script that downloads text only web pages and the rest of will enjoy the future. Oh wait, nevermind, <a href="http://www.fsf.org/blogs/rms/can-we-rescue-olpc-from-windows">Stallman deleted the wireless firmware from his laptop</a>...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disappointed in Google]]></title>
    <link href="http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2008/02/05/disappointed-in-google/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-05T12:38:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://patrick.wagstrom.net/weblog/2008/02/05/disappointed-in-google</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday, I had the chance to hear <a href="http://www.cmu.edu/">CMU</a> <a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/">SCS Ph.D.</a> alum, and president of <a href="http://www.g.cn/">Google China</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kai-Fu_Lee">Kai-Fu Lee</a> speak on the building Google China and what it means to do business in China versus the United States.  It reminded me of the fact that what we accept for "The Internet" -- Amazon, eBay, Google, Yahoo, Wikipedia, Flickr, etc -- isn't universal.  In fact, what we refer to as the "The Internet" barely exists in other markets.  Most American web companies that have invested in China have failed spectacularly -- never gaining market share, or buying the dominant Chinese firm and running them into the ground.  Dr. Lee made it clear that Google was planning for the long run and had no intention of being driven into the ground -- largely because they have the resources and are willing to burn lots of cash in the process of understand the market and developing tools to serve the market.</p>

<p>Throughout his presentation, he briefly mentioned a few of the political challenges around building companies in China.  For example, when he was listing how Chinese view western web products, for Wikipedia he listed "no access to wikipedia" and for MySpace he listed "periodic access to MySpace".  These garnered a chuckle out of the people in the audience, but they highlight very real issues with the Chinese governments attempts at censoring the net.  Google, for their part, has acquiesced to the Chinese government demands, and censored their search results.</p>

<p>An easy, and obvious example of this is doing a Google search for Tiananmen Square.  On the English language web, the top hits on this topic are related to the 1989 massacre there.  On the Chinese web it's all the articles you'd see about a square area in any large city.  Of course, most Chinese aren't going to be searching in English, rather they'd search for 天安门广场.  Comparing the images on <a href="http://images.google.com/images?hl=en&amp;q=%E5%A4%A9%E5%AE%89%E9%96%80%E5%BB%A3%E5%A0%B4&amp;btnG=Search+Images&amp;gbv=2">the US Google images search</a> and <a href="http://images.google.cn/images?hl=zh-CN&amp;q=%E5%A4%A9%E5%AE%89%E9%96%80%E5%BB%A3%E5%A0%B4&amp;btnG=%E6%90%9C%E7%B4%A2%E5%9B%BE%E7%89%87&amp;gbv=2&amp;aq=f">the Chinese Google images search</a> shows quite the difference.  For the US the first four images are typical info images, but then the subject quickly changes to the protest with the photo of the <a href="http://www.myoops.org/twocw/mit/NR/rdonlyres/40BE95B5-0D8B-4E4F-9F85-F10E3F5E1A16/0/dept17imagetanks.jpg">tank man</a> who defiantly stood in front of a column of Chinese tanks only to later be whisked away to who knows where.</p>

<p>According to Dr. Lee, the real reason for this is that Google tries to provide culturally relevant searches.  This makes some sense -- in the UK someone searching for Biscuits is looking for what we call Cookies here in the US.  They should not be subject to dozens of recipes for biscuits and gravy.  At the same time, most people above the age of 25 know the power of the protests in Tiananmen Square -- I was nine at the time and vividly remember the news and pictures out of China.  It's an aspect of Chinese history that has been washed away by the Chinese government -- only they can't erase the memory from the rest of the world.  It also sets a very dangerous precedent for companies operating in repressive regimes.  What if the protests from Burma, which were captured on <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/racoles/1437376279/in/set-72157602328689757/">Flickr</a> and numerous other sites, happened in China?  Would Google be obligated to censor such information at government decree?  The answer is probably yes, and I'm sure they would.</p>

<p>When pressured about the issue through a question which was much more weakly worded than what I would have used (I tried to get called on, but was in a bad position), Dr. Lee stated that Google's position was that they believed the Chinese people were better with their products than without.  Translation: "We'd really like to make money there, even if it does help out a repressive regime".  Will all this make me stop using Google products? No.  Does it change my views on Google?  Yes.  I'm very disappointed that a company that is so loved in the US has taken such a weak stance abroad.  They claim they have patience, if that's true, they should have the patience to not contribute to a corrupt totalitarian regimes effort to censor information for the purpose of maintaining a political elite with complete control.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
